<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>Home of Todd Libby - Senior Front End Developer</title>
	<subtitle>A web development, design and technology blog.</subtitle>
	<link href="https://toddl.dev/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://toddl.dev/"/>
	<updated>2020-08-24T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
	<id>https://toddl.dev/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Todd Libby</name>
		<email>toddlibby@protonmail.com</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>An Event Apart 2008 - Wrap-up Edition</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-boston-2008/"/>
		<updated>2008-04-30T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-boston-2008/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;preface&quot;&gt;Preface&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a super fanboy-ish post, but it is (100%) in its original entirety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-event-apart-2008%2C-boston%2C-ma&quot;&gt;An Event Apart 2008, Boston, MA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to take the time now to really sit down and write a comprehensive post on my experience at An Event Apart that took place this past Monday and Tuesday in Boston. I had been at the ready, saving what I could in time for the event and barely made it out of there with some pocket change. So be forewarned, don’t be frugal like me with little, and remember to bring your credit card and don’t leave home without it. (Where have I heard that before?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started writing this yesterday and have given this more attention again today. I wanted to write a very in-depth post about my experience and maybe “twist an arm” and if someone out there, even if it is one person reads this, goes to an AEA event and then writes back and says it was worth it, then it really was worth taking the extra couple days to write this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;off-for-an-adventure&quot;&gt;Off for an adventure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got out of my “9-5” job at 7:30 in the morning, went home, wanted to catch an hour or so of sleep. I caught 30 minutes. So I proceeded to go get ready and left for Boston. Now mind you, I don’t trek out very much with the price of gas and because a third shift job just sucks the will to live and the life force out of you. I did on this day, as I was looking forward to this event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So skipping over to when I got to the Marriott (after getting lost in Roxbury and all that good stuff that usually happens when I venture down to Boston) I forget the credit card and start to freak. Calming down the solution was found, all was good, but not after my first impression with Jeffrey Zeldman was probably one of psychotic insanity (if there is such a term.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My apologies to Jeffrey Zeldman and the folks at An Event Apart for having a complete and utter meltdown as I had the biggest anxiety attack to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally (after 2-3 hours of calls and instructions to fax over information so I could use the credit card) got to relax in the room, on the 34th floor. Big huge bed. BAM! Out like a prizefighter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-one.-meeting-%26-mingling&quot;&gt;Day One. Meeting &amp;amp; Mingling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I meet Jeffrey again, we chat and had lunch together it was great. I got to talk to Bruce Lawson and Eric Meyer for a bit as well during breakfast, things were &lt;strong&gt;A LOT&lt;/strong&gt; better. Went in and sat through the presentations, immersed in them all, mingled during breaks, took photos, had photos taken with speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing. I went up to my room to relax for a few minutes before the Opening Night party… I made the mistake of laying down on the big, huge comfy bed I had… out like a light. Damn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-two.-more-mingling-%26-me-being-me&quot;&gt;Day Two. More Mingling &amp;amp; Me Being Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mingling, eating, listening. Asked questions, got a book from Kimberly Blessing, tried to win a copy of Adobe CS3 if I got picked for a website critique from Jeffrey… unfortunately, that didn’t happen and 5 out of 6 of the people were Mac users… Scott Fegette, I will &lt;strong&gt;(GLADLY)&lt;/strong&gt; take a copy of the PC version if you feel the need to get rid of some!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of who I met. Everyone was great. I probably came off as a nervous tool, with nothing better to say and with a look like a 16-year-old rock band groupie, wide-eyed and drooling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeffrey Zeldman, Marci Eversole… made me feel welcomed and hopefully forgot about the fact I was acting like a raving lunatic on Sunday. EDIT: He did not, haha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeffrey was very accommodating and I had the chance of a lifetime to sit down and have lunch with him and talk and he actually liked the site. Handed me some useful information that I will be working on shortly as well. Autographed his book that I bought for me and we chatted and I kinda stalked him… no, I did. Sorry, Jeffrey!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eric Meyer. What can I say? Awed in the presence of another guru I have followed for a long time. very friendly and witty. When I told Bruce Lawson he saved my life with conditional comments, they both joked about how it was so proprietary. After the two kicks in the gut(j/k) I laughed, it was funny and yes, it was a stupid thing to say. I should have gone with, “FIRE!” Yes, Eric, I’d rather have your name in my book rather than oh, let’s say “Julio Iglesias” as your signing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bruce Lawson, friendly chap. Small guy. Him and Jeffrey, both small… or am I just tall (more on that later)? He and I chatted a bit, nice guy, all around. Saved my life with conditional comments, but as Eric Meyer put it, it was proprietary… so I don’t know if that was a good thing to say? Bruce is a friendly guy though, and his site states he prefers Guinness, so any guy who likes Guinness is alright in my book (as it is my preferred beverage in alcoholic nature of choice).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-speakers&quot;&gt;The speakers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AAll great and accessible. Although I didn’t ask a lot of questions, I did let the ones I have followed know that I have been a sort of “fan” for a long time. I figured they already had to field all the questions from 500 +/- other attendees. my favorites? All.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kimberly Blessing gave me something to shoot for. A Standards Manager job. I also won a book from her and Christopher Schmitt (among other writers)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ethan Marcotte gave me a refreshing way to make sure to communicate between coder and designer (a chore in itself for most of us).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason Santa Maria gave me a new thought on design and presentation. Jason also stirred up the passion I have for typography and his site is amazing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeffrey Veen made me think of data visualization. Made me re-live 1974 all over again, and how to incorporate users into the user experience. I would have loved to have sat down with him at the bar and had a beer, but I had to leave Boston that night, as I had to get back to my “reality” that is my full-time job. Jeffrey is 6´6˝, taller than me (one of two (Christopher Schmitt being the other) I really got to chat with) I felt short for a change… a very nice guy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jared Spool gave me a new perspective on navigation and the need for clear and conciseness when it comes to users finding their way around a site. He’s also one hell of a speaker and is super hilarious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christopher Fahey gave me insight on style and art direction when it comes to interactive design and to think about form and function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andy Budd opened my mind on user experience. I never thought about using everyday trips to a store or restaurant for example, as a gauge for user experience. Like my trip to an eatery, which I will describe later. One of the people I have looked to and read his books, he’s one of those that have helped me understand CSS a lot better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doug Bowman make me think about scaling. Will a site reach 10 people or 10 million? Is it ready, willing and capable? He also made me think of i18n (A numeronym for Internationalization. 18 letters between ‘i’ and ‘n’). make sure your site is ready for such a throng of an audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luke Wroblewski made me understand the user experience a lot better. Opened my eyes to what UX and UI is and gave me a peaked curiosity into UX/UI design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PPK made me realize that yes, Javascript really is simple and unobtrusive. Explaining it clearly, very clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eric Meyer just gave me new ideas on creating my own CSS framework and a reset stylesheet and a better understanding of browser behaviors. He also was very approachable and friendly, taking the time to talk to me just as if we had known each other for a while. One of the people I have followed, it was an honor to be able to just “hang out” and talk. He even signed his own name to the AEA book that we got as a guide to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and Jeffrey Zeldman gave me the experience of a lifetime. A figure I have been following and admiring for years, not only did he make me feel welcome and having lunch with him was the ultimate honor. Jeffrey showed me that it is alright to let people know what you do and to let you do it. That indeed, the web is not print and that people (some people) need to realize that, that it is alright to say, “This is what I do, let me do it and you will be pleased by the results.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met others like Christopher Schmitt, whom, I had talked to at lunch on Day One. Totally being the space cadet that I am and not realizing it was him who wrote the CSS Cookbook from O’Reilly. I was able to win a copy of “Adapting to Web Standards” so when I get some time I am going to sit down and read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my experience with meeting people in my chosen career path, my “Yoda’s” if you will. People I have followed and people I will follow and learn from hopefully. Everyone I spoke to that I just listed was absolutely nice, approachable, friendly, and has had or made a huge impact on what I do and will do in web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t thank them all enough for what they have done, what they have taught me and for opening my eyes and mind to what they spoke about. Two days of just “talking shop” really has made a difference and gave my batteries a much-needed recharge. I feel like there is so much to do and can be done, hopefully, I can apply what I have learned and make good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To anyone thinking of going, even if it is a trip from your area, I suggest you do it. There is no other experience (to date) that I have had that has made such an impact on me personally. I’m not really one for the huge venues, with throngs of people numbering the thousands, but 500 people or so there, it felt more personable and you actually had access to pick the minds and mingle socially with the speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something I will never forget. So thank you all who spoke and were involved in the planning and organizing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>An Event Apart 2017 - Wrap-Up Edition</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-boston-2017/"/>
		<updated>2017-05-19T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-boston-2017/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-event-apart-boston-2017%2C-boston%2C-ma&quot;&gt;An Event Apart Boston 2017, Boston, MA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I finally have some free time to sit down and collect my thoughts about the past couple of weeks that have been a whirlwind of activity. Here, however, is the wrap-up for An Event Apart that took place this past Monday through Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So without going into painfully long and exhaustingly minute detail, here’s the quick rundown, or as quick as I can relay the conference to any readers out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-one.-kickoff&quot;&gt;Day One. Kickoff&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeffrey Zeldman leads the conference off with “From Research to Redesign: An Unexpected Journey”. Talking about how design begins with the product, in the example he chose, was engagement rings. In my case, at my work, it is a web application that our clients use for automatic payroll deduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data, people, patterns, how to use your site to convey to visitors what your product is and how to do it clearly. Similarities to his talk and what I am undertaking at my work were strikingly parallel to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jaimee Newberry followed with The Art &amp;amp; Soul of Selling. This talk helped me in many crucial ways. I was glad to have been there for this one. Her 12 “Check Yourself Checkpoints” were fantastic. She touched on emails, word choices, and speaking with confidence that I had struggled to do in my entire professional career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Be Specific Immediately”, “Don’t Be A Jerk”, “Follow Up”. Some of the points she touched on. Especially the being specific immediately and word choices. Now I can take these, shorten my lengthy emails, with clear and concise emails that get the point across to our clients immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of “Well, I can look into this issue, but I’m not sure what the issue could be, it may consist of a number of things that I would have to look at.” I can now shorten that to, “I will look into this.” Simple as that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brad Frost then came up to the podium and spoke about the collaboration with others when working in teams. Mission statements and company values. I work with others, so this came in handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was touched on next, I found more intriguing and very useful. Brand style guides, code style guides, voice and tone style guides. Creating a design system at work. These are so very invaluable to me. More on research and priorities. Design principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I joked around when I thanked Brad for his talk, I told him he, “helped me exponentially broaden my bookmarks about 100X with all the great links to tools and examples, as well as things he has been working on.” There was a ton of information, notes, links and ideas I took away from Brad’s talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll leave out the bees, I went Twitter happy with that gif I think. Nah, unleash the bees!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-boston-2017/Brad%20Frost&quot; class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;This was still the best from Day One from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/brad_frost?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@brad_frost&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/aeabos?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#aeabos&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/tcOxG1lmAn&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/tcOxG1lmAn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Todd (@toddlibby) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/toddlibby/status/864309047226503172?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 16, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan Mall came on after Brad to discuss Gantt charts. No, actually it was about strategy with the design and development process. Collaboration, Should designers code? Should developers design? If they don’t, then it’s okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He spoke about CSS briefly, did a quick, “how-to” for folks that did not know CSS or how to code it, talked about tools, the 8-point grid and a host of other small topics that I found useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I may have asked a question very much way off-topic to what he had spoken about regarding clients/bosses and their penchants for “this is not the same color I see on my phone as it is here on your computer” when you copied the hex code as it was… I guess my question had to do with the process, so I may have not been as far off as I thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First-time speaker Laura Martini was next and gave a great talk about “Designing the Right Thing”. Designing needs for the business, the user and yourself. The HEART framework (Happiness, Engagement, Adoption, Retention, and Task Success).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laura dove into the NPS, CSAT, and CES scoring systems, do’s and don’t(s), tools and research. She gave a great talk for her first at An Event Apart and it helped me out and gave me some invaluable information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Coyier, the guy (or one of the people) behind CodePen and CSS-Tricks finished off the first day with a talk on SVG. Something I have been reading about, looking into, and trying to adopt for what seems like ages. Of course, I spaced at the fact I sat and had lunch at his table one afternoon. That&#39;s where my head was…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m basically going to leave this at, why wasn’t I using SVG more often on the projects I had done Chris wrapped up the day nicely and I had a ton of notes to take with me, go over and bring back some great ideas to work. The day was a long one, but the information up to this point from all the speakers was phenomenal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-two.-the-code-block&quot;&gt;Day Two. The Code Block&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Val Head spoke about “Animation in Design Systems and Process”. Communication, storyboards, and sketches. Motion comps, interactive prototypes. Tools to use when you’re creating things of the animated nature!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defining your brand. Brand &amp;amp; Experience Pillars, Voice &amp;amp; Tone, building animation guidelines. Documenting your decisions, durations, easing values and a host of other tidbits in the animation design and documentation process that really gave me ideas for the redesign of the company site I work for. Thanks for the time to chat with you Val!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel Andrew and Jen Simmons followed. What they both spoke about, the CSS Grid Layout, was the meat and potatoes of what I went to the conference for. Rachel spoke about the browser history briefly, how Firefox, Chrome, Safari, and Opera all adopted the CSS Grid support in their respective browsers. IE had yet to support it fully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel spoke about the Grid layout and showed some code examples, a great example was a magazine layout she built in front of all us attendees. Rachel also touched on Media Objects, auto as &lt;code&gt;flex-basis&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;minmax()&lt;/code&gt; as well as Feature Queries to name a few. An eye-opening look into what I had been questioning myself for since I was hired at the company I work for. An incredible talk that was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jen followed touching on the web when it first came out to the public, table-based layouts, and the evolution up to all the different sized mobile devices used these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grid systems, frameworks, all the different tools we see to help us build magazine style-layouts and column framework systems. Then unleashing the best thing I heard yet that day… CSS Grid also uses &lt;strong&gt;rows&lt;/strong&gt; as well as columns!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say… things happened in my head… Mind Blown!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/xT0xeJpnrWC4XWblEk/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Tim &amp; Eric mind blown gif&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jen went into a little about CSS Grid layouts (which I will get to soon. If you have read this far… you’re a trooper) but the meat and potatoes of this was in the third day, A Day Apart. Touched on tracks not having to be the same size, content sized by the size of a track, tracks sized by the content, the viewport, storyboards, overlap, framing, white space, verticality, flexibility and creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eric Meyer stepped up and spoke about “Design for Real Life”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-boston-2017/Eric%20Meyer&quot;&gt;When you design for interaction, you’re creating abstract rules to take unknown content and organize it in an unknown medium for presentation to unknown people who have largely unknown personal contexts.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The example Eric used, was Facebook. Facebook and their “On This Day” to be exact. People have things that happen in their lives that they really want to leave behind in the grieving process, Well, “On This Day” does not allow for that to happen. OTD brings up painful memories for people. Eric &amp;amp; myself included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/colabottles/image/upload/v1585002454/images/onthisday_ablvla.jpg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/colabottles/image/upload/v1585002454/images/onthisday_ablvla.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Example of Facebook filter for On This Day&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Now Facebook allows users to go in and filter people or dates.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It brought me back to when I remember reading his book, “&lt;em&gt;CSS: The Definitive Guide&lt;/em&gt;”, following him closely as I could in the CSS Working Group and wherever I could as he was (and still is) one of the most influential people in my life that brought me to my career path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember when I read the In Memoriam page, wanting to say something, not sure if he would read it, not sure if there was anything I could say that hadn’t been said already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I follow him because of the work he does in the field that I love. I was fortunate to be able to sit with Eric during lunches and the last day for a bit. Though not a huge talker, not wanting to interrupt anyone, not wanting to feel like a nuisance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time I saw, met and heard Eric was in Boston in 2008. It was like catching up with a friend. I enjoyed the time he gave me and appreciated it. Through his rough time, I saw a man who kept going in his professional life. This led me to not give up, this led me to keep fighting the fight daily. His strength during one of the worst times a parent could ever live through made me realize my small, luxury problems were just that, insignificant and petty. Eric is a power of example to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the other examples were of Pokemon Go. When people were walking in front of cars, on private property, crossing the border into Canada… warning modals stating that users need to be careful and stay alert when playing the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instances where A tweet by Juliana Hatfield with a track on it was flagged by Twitter for having her track in it, the “Cheatin’uh?” error that was (and still is?) on WordPress and had a seven (yes, SEVEN) year support thread going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason Grigsby then came on and spoke on “The Case for Progressive Web Apps”. Some of his points he touched on were the case between mobile web versus native apps, what is a PWA? and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not every customer or potential customer will install your native app, how people just stop using apps after a day, a week, or a month. You should provide a secure site or app for your web customers. Providing a fast experience for your users just to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if my company decides to roll out an app (which is highly doubtful at this time) then I have this to fall back on and use. “Not all users will add your web app to their home screen”. Our dependence on a mobile app is probably nil, but we do have a web app accessible through a browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I take this info and store it so I can access it and at some point, there may be a mobile app of some sort?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To wrap the second day up, Josh Clark, who in my opinion, gave me a lot to think about, which is okay. I could use the challenge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Josh touched upon machine learning, pattern processing, personal data, image recognition, language and speech recognition. Artificial Intelligence (AI). Some of which made me think, especially the fact that if you type something to post on Facebook, that for instance, may be angry, and erase it because you don’t want people to think you’re going to go out on a murder spree… Facebook retains that data and you don’t even know it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was taken back by that little revelation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexa ordering dollhouses when people that watched a newscast and had their Amazon Echo on, when the newscaster said, “Alexa, order me a dollhouse”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The invasive Burger King ad that triggered Google Home devices and a parrot that placed an order on an Amazon Echo because the Echo cannot tell if it is a parrot or human talking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google’s “Featured” snippets. Josh touched on accuracy over speed, allow for ambiguity, adding human judgment, embracing multiple systems, make it easy to contribute data and some other topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some shocking examples. I don’t remember the gentlman’s name, but he is of Asian heritage, and his photo did not meet the criteria of a site because it stated… “Subject eyes are closed”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google tagging blacks as “Gorillas”, Microsoft’s failed “Tay” who went from excitable teen to white supremacist in 0.4 seconds. Or possibly the worst case of machine bias was this…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The talk from Josh was incredibly eye-opening and valuable as I look at data differently now. Carefully thinking of how we, at my work, present our data. He ended Day Two in stellar fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-three.-a-day-apart&quot;&gt;Day Three. A Day Apart&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jen Simmons. CSS Grid Layouts. Five or so hours of going over layouts, writing modes, alignment, logical properties, and a little Flexbox. Mostly though it was an introduction to the CSS Grid Layout. Nothing really in-depth, because in the words of Eric Meyer, whom which I was seated next to this day, “It would take three days to go through everything.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A phenomenal(yes, again) and fantastic glimpse into the CSS Grid layout. With examples and questions from the audience, and a quote that I really liked, from another person I had met in 2008 at the same event, Bruce Lawson, she put up on a slide to make a point about writing modes;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-boston-2017/Bruce%20Lawson&quot;&gt;It’s the World Wide Web, not the Wealthy Western Web.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brucelawson.co.uk/2008/an-event-apart-boston/&quot;&gt;Funny story related to that encounter but that’s for another day.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I recommend this event to everyone in the creative field. A must-go, a must-attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly. I arrived in Boston looking forward to seeing Jeffrey Zeldman again and did so. Like with Eric Meyer, it felt like I was catching up with a friend. Jeffrey is one of the two (again, along with Eric) that shaped the way I thought about the web and helped me stay the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was gracious in allowing me to hang around and during a break, we spoke in great length with Claudia Snell and we spoke of things we had in common. It was nice not to feel alone in this crazy world, that there were others that have had similar issues and have walked through hell and kept on walking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For that, I am very grateful. I was probably (again) like a groupie or roadie hanging around backstage at a concert. AEA was my concert. I enjoy connecting with people in this field, I enjoy talking to and following the people that speak. I try not to intrude too deeply, keep a distance as to not seem like I’m some character like Jim Carrey’s character Chip Douglas in The Cable Guy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, I felt like I was in a room filled with people I follow and enjoy reading their books, speaking to, corresponding with and following online to see how they are professionally doing, and in real life. Many don’t know me, but they work they do, has helped me, helped shape me, and helped me be the professional I am today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even going back to 2008 when I met Jeff Veen, Doug Bowman, Jason Santa Maria, Andy Budd, and listened to the keynotes from Kimberly Blessing, Peter-Paul Koch, Ethan Marcotte, Jared Spool, Christopher Fahey, and Luke Wroblewski to the folks I met that I named previously. I can’t even begin to describe the gratitude that I have still, and now, for what they have done to help me in my career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even the folks at other AEA events that I did not see but always said, “I’ll be down next year!” to which I never was. People like Jeremy Keith, Andy Clarke, Dan Cederholm, Mark Boulton, Karen McGrane, Lea Verou, Mike Monteiro, Sarah Parmenter, Kristina Halvorson, Paul Irish, Jon Hicks, and Cameron Moll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2008, I took back information and used it to do the job I was hired to do then. 2017, I intend to do the same with the plethora of information I brought home with me. It took me 9 years and a lot of blood, sweat, and tears to get back to where I am today and get back to see these professionals speak. It was well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a speaker that I have misquoted or misconstrued the information somehow, please feel free to drop me a line or comment, to make a correction. I appreciate your time, thank you, and want to convey the information correctly to anyone interested in reading this novel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with that, I finally end this post. My apologies to all if you suffered through this, thank you for reading this if you got this far.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Maine Lobster Run 2017</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/maine-lobster-run-2017/"/>
		<updated>2017-09-03T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/maine-lobster-run-2017/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The trip entailed a five-day jaunt up the Maine coast starting in Kittery, Maine at Bob&#39;s Clam Hut who has one of the best lobster rolls in southern Maine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;i&#39;ve-only-met-two-lobster-rolls-i-didn&#39;t-like&quot;&gt;I&#39;ve Only Met Two Lobster Rolls I Didn&#39;t Like&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But they weren&#39;t at any place on the coast. They were at places that were inland, which is why I go to very few places inland to get a delicious lobster roll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up at these two places:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.redseatsmaine.com/&quot;&gt;Red&#39;s Eats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mainelobsterfestival.com/&quot;&gt;Maine Lobster Festival&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Red&#39;s. Best lobster roll in Maine. Bar none.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way up Route 1 I stopped into Ken&#39;s Restaurant, The Lobster Shack at Two Lights, and Red&#39;s Eats. The goal was reaching the Maine Lobster Festival for three days of seafood. I was already more than full, I was bursting at the seams, but I made it to Rockland, Maine safely. Now the fun begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only is there seafood that is fresh and great, but there is fair food, Amato&#39;s Real Italians (A Maine thing), and more fair food!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;that&#39;s-a-lot-of-lobster!&quot;&gt;That&#39;s a lot of lobster!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, yes it is. But for me it was well worth it. And I will do it again!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>An Event Apart 2018 - Wrap-Up Edition</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-boston-2018/"/>
		<updated>2018-05-27T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-boston-2018/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-event-apart-boston-2018%2C-boston%2C-ma&quot;&gt;An Event Apart Boston 2018, Boston, MA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally posted on my old site in installments, this has been compiled into one post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today started off, three days of design and web at the Renaissance Boston. So running on no sleep for the past 40 hours, I toughed out a fantastic first day of speakers at An Event Apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with every AEA, it was kicked off by Jeffrey Zeldman, speaking first about Engagement and the Content Performance Quotient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-boston-2018/Jeffrey%20Zeldman&quot;&gt;If a customer spends 30 minutes on our site, was she engaged&amp;hellip; or frustrated?&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speed of Usefulness, how quickly can you get the right content to your customer? How quickly can you solve their problem? What is the shortest distance between the problem and the solution?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content Performance Quotient (CPQ). The time it takes your customer to get the information she came for. The time it takes for a specific customer to find, receive, and absorb your most important content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-boston-2018/Jeffrey%20Zeldman&quot;&gt;FAQs are the junk drawer of content.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeffrey always kicks off AEA with relevant and thought-provoking talks. It made me think about the site for the company I work for and the “FAQ”-t, we have one item on the FAQ. The fact that the site is “pretty garbage”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, Jeffery delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up, was Yesenia Perez-Cruz who spoke about Scenario-Driven Design Systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A unified design system is essential to building better and faster; better because a cohesive experience is more easily understood by our users, and faster because it gives us a common language to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good design system feels cohesive, unified and connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Successful design patterns don’t exist in a vacuum. Successful design systems start with content and people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The differences between a successful design system and telling the story of her experience at Vox Media. The best way I saw her talk put…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-boston-2018/Jeffrey%20Zeldman&quot; class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;.&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/yeseniaa?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@yeseniaa&lt;/a&gt; killed it at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/aeabos?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#aeabos&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;mdash; zeldman (@zeldman) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zeldman/status/1011270559697645568?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 25, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, she did. what I took away from her talk was to let your user&#39;s needs define the building blocks you will need for your design system (if you even need one… more on that shortly). I can carry this to the table when I get back to the office and weigh heavily if we do indeed need a design system or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up was Una Kravets, who spoke on “Why Design Systems Fail”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Design System can be a style guide or visual pattern library. It can also be design tooling, a component library, voice and tone guidelines, design usage documentation and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been contemplating a design system and pattern library since I saw Brad Frost speak last year. We may be too small to do so, I have a lot of research to do, but a lot was clarified by Una today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is a design system? (Something I had a little insight into from last year’s talk and now this one), Why Design Systems fail, what are some characteristics of a happy design system. communication between devs and design, solid architecture, buy-in. The list goes on and on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She showed some examples of design systems, voice and tone, MailChimp, DigitalOcean, Carbon, Solid, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A successful design system is like a successful exercise program. Once you stop using it, you lose all your progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve never had a successful diet, so I will shoot for a successful design system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much to soak in after the first half of the first day today, and then after a quick lunch, a surprise (to me, I wasn’t expecting this part) Mike Essl who had designed the website, many moons ago for They Might Be Giants. A site I used to visit daily and I loved the look!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mike spoke about Cooper Union, the school he attended and all the rich history of people that attended and the things they had contributed to the world was staggering, to say the least! That school has had some rich history and very prolific people walk through their halls, indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same Bat-Time! Same Bat-Channel! His love for Batman and the massive resume Mike has is absolutely stunning and impressive some of the work that he has done or contributed to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The began the second half to the day and the part of the day I was waiting for, some more light shed on CSS Grids and the new direction of web design and CSS by the next three speakers, Rachel Andrew, Eric Meyer, and Jen Simmons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel started with “Graduating to Grid”. Telling the audience to understand CSS, you don’t have to memorize everything, just have a great understanding of it. Understanding the cascade, of Cascading Style Sheets, inheritance, specificity. You don’t need a grid-based solution to everything, build your own framework, and Rachel even spoke about Bootstrap! &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;GASP!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-boston-2018/Rachel%20Andrew&quot;&gt;Don’t be afraid of the future of CSS Grids, be excited!&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Eric Meyer took the stage to discuss Feature Queries. What are the pros and cons? Where are the strengths and weaknesses?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feature Queries examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token atrule&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token rule&quot;&gt;@supports&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;prop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; val&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;/* CSS goes here */&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token atrule&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token rule&quot;&gt;@supports&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;--css&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; variables&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token selector&quot;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;        &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;--color1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; navy&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;        &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;--color2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; red&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token selector&quot;&gt;html.help&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;        &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;--color1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; teal&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;        &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;--color2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; maroon&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token selector&quot;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;        &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;--color1&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token selector&quot;&gt;.highlight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;        &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;--color2&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token atrule&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token rule&quot;&gt;@supports&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;prop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; val&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;/* CSS goes here */&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token atrule&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token rule&quot;&gt;@supports&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;--css&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; variables&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token selector&quot;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;--color1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; navy&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;--color2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; red&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token selector&quot;&gt;html.help&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;--color1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; teal&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;--color2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; maroon&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token selector&quot;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;--color1&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token selector&quot;&gt;.highlight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;--color2&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to put all these new CSS features to work for you right away? I’m going to do a lot of experimentation with these features soon, I hope. Another great talk by Eric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the day ended with Jen Simmons discussing the phases of the web that we have seen throughout the history of the web. From simple HTML to Responsive Web Design (RWD), Jen has brought forth the term Intrinsic Web Design to the forefront.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truncation joke was a good one as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/colabottles/image/upload/v1585002461/images/truncation_wnesil.jpg&quot; data-src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/colabottles/image/upload/v1585002461/images/truncation_wnesil.jpg&quot; class=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;A slide from Jen Simmons talk on Intrinsic Web Design at An Event Apart Boston 2018&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is so much that can be done with web layout these days and it is exciting, Jen touched on some key points on ways to contract and expand space, new possibilities for flexibility, columns and units, change in how we use the viewport, and programming to all four edges of the viewport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel and Jen both have been the catalyst for changing the way we look at the web today, and I am very grateful and fortunate to have seen them both speak for two years running now. They have both shed light on CSS Grid and I understand a lot better now than I did when I went into AEA last year by miles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…and I cannot forget to mention that I got to see my friend Claudia Snell again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a speaker and happen to see this, and if there is anything I missed upon, key points perhaps, then please reach out and I can certainly add those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-two&quot;&gt;Day Two&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it is finished and as usual the second day of speakers was as good as the first!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeremy Keith kicked the day off with his talk and what a talk it was! The way the web is changing it can be overwhelming and exhausting. What tools should you learn and use and how long will those tools be around?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeremy brought everyone in attendance back in time, discussed the present state and walked us on a tour of the future in working on the web. From HTML/CSS/JS to frameworks and libraries and all the way to Progressive Web Apps, Jeremy taught us if we learn from the past, we can make sensible choices in the future regarding our work on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-boston-2018/Todd%20Libby&quot; class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;Internet Pace Layers with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/adactio?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@adactio&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/aeabos?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#aeabos&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/3U1C6ETHEz&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/3U1C6ETHEz&lt;/a&gt; &amp;mdash; Todd (@toddlibby) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/toddlibby/status/1011602011048038402?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 26, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then on to Donna Lichaw, who taught us on how to convey a story to your customers/clients. The better the story, the more likely you will want to use a product, pay for a product, tell others about the product. A “story first” approach to building websites, apps, and more that draw customers in, get them excited and keep them engaged for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-boston-2018/Donna%20Lichaw&quot; class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;The better the STORY behind your product, the more likely folks are to try it, continue to use it, pay to use it, and recommend it to others. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dlichaw?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@dlichaw&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/aeabos?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#aeabos&lt;/a&gt;&amp;mdash; zeldman (@zeldman) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zeldman/status/1011620432028545024?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 26, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make things that go &lt;strong&gt;BOOM!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then on to Val Head who brought to the table this year, Building More Expressive Products. Using animation and sound, you can bring a whole new level to the sites you create or the projects you are working on and Val showed us a little bit of how to harness the design details from motion and sound to build overarching themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using examples from TunnelBear, Authentic Weather and MailChimp, and the way they use animation to express their brand with personality. How we style for animation and what feelings do we aim for. Calm? Strong? Energetic? Animation on the web can bring a website or brand to a whole new level of personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After lunch, the panel opened up with Rachel Andrew and Jeremy Keith. Discussing the positives (as well as the negatives) of working with CSS Grid Layout and how we can begin leveling up our Grid skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trent Walton followed up the lunch hour with his talk on third-party scripts, how many we have loading on our sites, ways to check the speed of our sites with all the stuff we have loading on them and to be honest (when I ran a check) I nearly fell over in my chair on how much it takes and how fast it is to load my old site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trent also shared ways to include third-party scripts and services on our sites. Benefits and concerns about those third-party scripts. Using your ad blocker versus not and seeing the difference with the preferred browser inspector of your choice. A great talk and his first time speaking at AEA. Job well done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delivering a performant, accessible, responsive, scalable website isn’t enough: I also need to consider the impact of third-party scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derek Featherstone followed with his talk on Inclusive UX. His slides and talk had Star Wars integrated into it, so I was hooked at the start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-boston-2018/Derek%20Featherstone&quot;&gt;Accessibility is an outcome. Inclusive design is a process.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inclusive UX Design is “the intentional facilitation and crafting of the interactions within an ecosystem that incorporates inclusion as a core value.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking about communication with all involved early in the process can make things a lot easier through the rest of the process. Reverse engineering a site, basically breaking it down in pieces to see where things are not right or went wrong. A great example was a site that had some pretty sketchy colors and a flyout menu that went three-wide and covered a lot of content area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Color palettes that are good and bad for accessibility, design intention, CSS class name reviews, high contrast tweaks… a lot of stuff regarding accessibility to soak in, well worth the price of admission!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to wrap up Day Two was Gerry McGovern who brought the house down with a great, humorous talk about Intuitive Navigation, and do I mean bringing the house down with laughter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussing sites that it seems like it takes an eternity to finally get to the point of what the navigation was for. In a couple cases, the Gatwick Airport and Brussels Airport just to get online at these airports took 5 or more steps through a process to connect! And the right way to do it, Dublin Airport. Click once and you’re connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-boston-2018/Gerry%20McGovern&quot; class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;Designing an intuitive navigation - Gerry McGovern&amp;#39;s presentation at An Event Apart 2018 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/customerexperience?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#customerexperience&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/informationarchitecture?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#informationarchitecture&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/e4ySp0WLjl&quot;&gt;https://t.co/e4ySp0WLjl&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/aeabos?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#aeabos&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/aeaboston?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#aeaboston&lt;/a&gt;&amp;mdash; Gerry McGovern (@gerrymcgovern) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gerrymcgovern/status/1011675900482596865?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;June 26, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a humorous trip through the navigations of some example sites that had me in stitches, as well as the entire crowd. Icons for navigation, “Most Popular” navigation blocks, labeled versus unlabeled icons, hidden versus unhidden menu systems that result in huge losses in daily engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even why and how to avoid (or even kill) the hamburger menu (something I am guilty of implementing on a few sites).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned to reduce confusion and increase speed and simplicity for our customers at the company I work for, and had a lot of hearty laughter while learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That wrapped up Day Two. As much as I would like to add more quotes, pictures and details, I have got to get some sleep. Tomorrow will be a very long day. I’ll have a wrap-up on the entire day tomorrow late. Tomorrow consists of A Day Apart, with Eric Meyer. “Navigating the CSS Renaissance”. I look forward to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time, that is all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-day-apart-with-eric-meyer&quot;&gt;A Day Apart with Eric Meyer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was sadly enough, the last day of the conference. A Day Apart with Eric Meyer. A full day with Eric capped it off in style… literally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went through some examples of Grid, flexbox, production features that are ready to roll and we can use now. Writing modes, the fact that now, we actually can use the web like we did and do with print.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feature and media queries. Positioning of objects and making them fit in the viewport, shadows, borders, auto margins, shaping content and so much more! definitely worth the extra day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All-in-all, it was a fantastic three days of design and code. Phenomenal speakers, a great crowd, a great venue. It surpassed my expectations. It was in a new venue, new location, so I wasn’t so sure, but now that it has come and gone, it was well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got up the courage to talk and mingle with most of the speakers. Got to meet Jeremy Keith, after all these years. I went in 2008, I believe Jeremy came back in 2010, I wasn’t able to and did not attend until last year. So it was a thrill for me, fanboy moment. First site I linked to was Jeremy’s and I have 4 of his books. (&lt;em&gt;HTML5 For Web Designers&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Bulletproof Ajax&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;DOM Scripting&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Going Offline&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to ramble, so I think I did a little bit when talking, but the amount of great information, from great speakers, that are very friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend anyone thinking of going, go. Get your company to let you go, get them to send you there, make your pitch and sell them on it to advance your knowledge. You will be sure to leave there feeling like you have gained a lifetime of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to see Jeffrey and Eric again and fanboy out like I always do, talk with them, they were so very gracious and put up with my fawning over the event like I always do and just have fun for three days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to all the speakers. I apologize for my over-enthusiastic fanboy-ing, fawning and swooning like I do each year beacause this is the best conference by far for front-end fossils like myself. Tremendous jobs from all! Thank you to those behind the scenes, that set it up and make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>UX Burlington 2019</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/ux-burlington-2019/"/>
		<updated>2019-05-02T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/ux-burlington-2019/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;ux-burlington-2019---burlington%2C-vt&quot;&gt;UX Burlington 2019 - Burlington, VT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;my-first-ux-burlington&quot;&gt;My First UX Burlington&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While scanning the countryside for conferences in the New England area, I was drawn to UX Burlington. So I snagged a ticket. Best decision I made that week. More on the food that I had there on Church Street as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;morning-keynote&quot;&gt;Morning Keynote&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Victor Yocco gave the morning keynote. “Designing For Short Attention Spans”. A great way to kick off the conference. Filled with humor, light-heartedness and information, I was glad I had attended because this keynote made me think about a lot of UX things I&#39;ve been dealing with at work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three main points of the talk were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&#39;s an Attention Span?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decision Making Heuristics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tactical Design Elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have an attention span that is less than that of a goldfish. Designers need to care about their users&#39; attention though. Victor touched upon the questions we have to be asking not only our team and stakeholders, but for our users as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/ux-burlington-2019/Victor%20Yocco&quot;&gt;Designing to gain people&#39;s attention comes with great responsibility. Why do you want that, what are you doing that&#39;s contributing to making their lives better if they&#39;re going to give you their attention?&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of tech giants need to start asking themselves that very question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the many points touched on in the fantastic morning keynote were;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to capture users&#39; attention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to understand why we want and deserve users&#39; attention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We must navigate ethical decisions and issues when we design for attention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to conduct research with users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users can&#39;t pay close attention to each decision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heuristics are mental shortcutsfor making decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accounting for heuristics may increase user adoption and decrease mental load.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some key points on the Tactical Design Elements were;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear the clutter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove distractions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Animation. What is the goal of it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give users something to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was so much to Victor&#39;s talk, it would take me a day to just relay the vast amount of information that was crammed into a 48-minute video. I had three pages of notes myself, so I&#39;ll just suggest people watch the video of the keynote. The link to &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/6WBS6YYMAcE&quot;&gt;the video for Victor&#39;s keynote can be found here&lt;/a&gt; on the UX Burlington YouTube account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;fr%C3%A9d%C3%A9ric-harper&quot;&gt;Frédéric Harper&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first speaker that I saw on the developer track was Frédéric Harper, “Building Web Apps That Don’t Suck”. Frédéric spoke about tips and tricks to help you optimize your applications. Create a great experience for your users that is fast and with quality. It was a great way to kick off the developer track for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frédéric touched upon mobile first, engagement with mobile apps. Why are you using the application? Keep your users engaged with a great UI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about content, think about the comfort zone of the screen and what users ahve to do to navigate your app and he even broke into a little condensed version of Fitt&#39;s Law. Fitt&#39;s Law, for those who don&#39;t know, is a predictive model of human movement primarily used in human–computer interaction and ergonomics. Basically, the law predicts that the time required to rapidly move to a target area is a function of the ratio between the distance to the target and the width of the target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minimizing large files, file requests, HTTP requests, using a CDN, running the audit on Webhint, don&#39;t make users think about the interface, insulate them from the complexities and make our goals easier and faster. There was an awful lot of information packed into the hour and I&#39;ll point you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/DWd5cL3ViTY&quot;&gt;Frédéric&#39;s video on the UX Burlington YouTube page&lt;/a&gt;. I highly suggest watching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;henri-helvetica&quot;&gt;Henri Helvetica&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next speaker was Henri Helvetica, “Planet of the APIs: A Tale of Performance and UX”. The beginning of Henri&#39;s talk was about the good old days of Mosaic, data and web origins such as in November of 2016 (not so long ago) when mobile and tablet internet usage surpassed desktop internet usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How the US was 2nd in the world with selling the low end/low spec phones &amp;amp; devices, performance on mobile, and how 53% of visitors will abandon a page after 3 seconds and 77% of pages load in 10 seconds or more with the average page loading in 19 seconds. Want to know exactly how long 19 seconds is? If Henri doesn&#39;t mind, I&#39;ll borrow this example that he used. Buckle up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&quot;yt&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GWbP8eC-SIw?start=20&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t say I did not warn you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a quote from Henri I loved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/ux-burlington-2019/Henri%20Helvetica&quot;&gt;Resource loading is a delicate dance that can be delightful, but also destructivedue to device damper and limitations.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&#39;t (and possibly have not a chance to explain these as well as Henri did) go into the API&#39;s in-depth, but I will give you and overview of what they are and &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/DLvSPYklE4U&quot;&gt;point you to the video on the UX Burlington YouTube page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paint Timing API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intersection Observer API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Media Capabilities API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network Information API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cache API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Battery Status API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll go back to another quote from Henri;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/ux-burlington-2019/Henri%20Helvetica&quot;&gt;You can&#39;t improve what you don&#39;t measure.&lt;/blockquote&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;I had written down a lot of notes, what mobile browsers these are all good in and not implemented in yet, but again, I&#39;ll direct and suggest that &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/DLvSPYklE4U&quot;&gt;folks go to the UX Burlington YouTube page and view his talk there&lt;/a&gt;. Henri articulated everything so well, I don&#39;t want to butcher it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;chris-demars&quot;&gt;Chris DeMars&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris DeMars was the last speaker for the day with “Focusing on Focus”. He nailed it. I had corresponded with Chris (@saltnburnem) on Twitter so it was a treat to see and hear his talk on Focusing on Focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started with this after Chris&#39; introduction;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&quot;yt&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XB4cjbYywqg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and a quote that I hope Chris doesn&#39;t mind me borrowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/ux-burlington-2019/Chris%20DeMars&quot;&gt;If now, you were on the fence about accessibility because it was always an afterthought it&#39;s never thought of from the beginning. I hope, (after the talk) you can go back and reflect on what your why is. And at some point you&#39;ll understand &amp;lsquo;Wow, I need to do this not just for myself.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the World Heath Organization, 20% of the people on Earth have a disability(impairment). The W3C states;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/ux-burlington-2019/W3C&quot;&gt;Web accessibility means that people with disabilities &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; use the web.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris thinks (and I am in total agreement) it &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; read;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/ux-burlington-2019/Chris%20DeMars&quot;&gt;Web accessibility means that &lt;em&gt;EVERYONE&lt;/em&gt; can use the web.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/gUK0ieCJkRI&quot;&gt;Go to the UX Burlington page on YouTube and see the video in its entirety.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris also walked people through &lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;:focus&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;:focus-visible&lt;/span&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;:focus-within&lt;/span&gt; with some pretty cool, yet simple pens over at his CodePen account. &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/chrisdemars/pen/OvrbLr&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;:focus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/chrisdemars/pen/PRXbpg&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;:focus-within&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/chrisdemars/pen/ejbZYv&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;and focus styles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; so go check those out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Top notch accessibility talk from Chris, so I was extra glad I got the ticket I got.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dr.-robert-moore&quot;&gt;Dr. Robert Moore&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Witht the closing keynote on a great one-day conference was Dr. Robert Moore and “Conversational UX”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without going into it, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/ZcKB2ns8I1g&quot;&gt;go watch the video&lt;/a&gt;. I couldn&#39;t even possibly begin to articulate a fraction of good as Dr. Moore does. I&#39;ll give it the Reader&#39;s Digest version as well as I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversational UX. When dealing with the technologies we have out there, chatbots and voice assistants, there is a lack of conversational feel to them and Dr. Moore tells you how there is (and has been) work going on in the field of conversational science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Moore shows you a little bit about what they are doing at IBM and the interaction patterns they are working on and with to make conversational patterns and UX better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;but-what-about-the-food%3F&quot;&gt;But what about the Food?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I decided to go out for dinner after I got into Burlington the day before the conference. I decided upon the Asiana Noodle Shop and oh my, was I glad I did. Located on Chruch Street in the heart of the Church Street Marketplace, it is a well-hidden place, so you have to look hard for it or you&#39;ll miss it. At least I had to. I am oblivious some times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed (understatement) the Korean BBQ short ribs and bibimbap. Along with a terrific wonton soup. Nice cozy little place located downstairs, busy place, but the food is out of this world. That&#39;s a must-do if you&#39;re looking for good eats in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s just a little recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;yeah%2C-but-the-conference!&quot;&gt;Yeah, but the conference!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference, for a one-day event, is terrific! Well put together, fantastic speakers (check out the past speakers and videos on YouTube), great food (poke bowls were phenomenal) and a great crowd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are debating on going, debate no more. Go. It&#39;s well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>An Event Apart 2019 - Wrap-Up Edition</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-boston-2019/"/>
		<updated>2019-05-08T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-boston-2019/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-event-apart-boston-2019%2C-boston%2C-ma&quot;&gt;An Event Apart Boston 2019, Boston, MA&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-one&quot;&gt;Day One&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was terrific. Jeffrey started it off with his talk about slow design. There is too much going on, on websites that distract and stresses users. Designers should help users by slowing down so they can make informed decisions. &lt;span class=&quot;italic&quot;&gt;“Readability transcends legibility”&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;italic&quot;&gt;“Absorption, not conversion&lt;/span&gt;.” Where you read from, lying down? Sitting in a chair tablet on your knees? At the breakfast table with the tablet proped up a foot away from you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minamalism and whitespace (macro and micro) for focus and being less busy, big typography for readability and hierarchy for accessibility were among the many points Jeffrey touched upon in his fantastic talk that kicked off another phenomenal conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mina Markham followed up with a phenomenal talk about art direction and inclusiveness. Mina also spoke about progressive enhancement and how we have to make sure users have an experience on their own terms that is the experience they want. A great one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Localization was brought to my attention and the fact that not everyone is from North America (United States) and reading what I create. Localization is important, let&#39;s make it so. Though at work we are not used outside of the United States, we probably wouldn&#39;t use localization but should anyhow. Mina talked about adjusting design, illustration and photos to a different country or culture by using the examples of her work at Slack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Val Head followed with making motion inclusive. I always enjoy the animation parts of the conference, especially when Val speaks. The energy and enthusiasm are contagious. Her talking points being we shouldn&#39;t be using unnecessary animations, subtilty in animation (opacity, colors, movement), triggering motion in GIFs and video, and using &lt;code&gt;prefers-reduced-motion&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Val spoke about which types of motion can be triggers for people with disabilities. Now I haven&#39;t used motion much in the projects I have worked on, but intend to and this talk was just what I needed. I suffer from migraines, so when I am on the computer and must be (whether working at the office or otherwise) some animation can be hard on the eyes, so I had to take that into consideration for persons with more than just a migraine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eric Meyer then spoke about CSS generated content. This was one of my cringe moments, but more on that later. I called this block the &lt;span class=&quot;bolder&quot;&gt;“Technical Triad of Terrific”&lt;/span&gt; because the next three speakers I follow closely and anything they share or write up on CSS, Grid Layout, and web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eric talked about the possibilities when using the pseudo-elements &lt;code&gt;::before&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;::after&lt;/code&gt; for styling and minimalising the clutter in your HTML markup. Then how pull quotes are “mismanaged” and that&#39;s when I had my cringe moment. I thought I had borrowed a cool pull quote design in a blockquote from a site then tailored it even better but nay. I say nay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will also say, as I get older, and as I go to these conferences, I get tired easily which is why I like to get up during the intermissions and walk around and mingle. I dozed off during Eric&#39;s talk for an embarrassing amount of time. Something that I still feel horrible about because his technical talks are some of the best I have heard no matter what the topic. So I suffer from embarrassment and remorse over that. A good reminder to get more sleep during conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel Andrew crushed it with her talk on redefining the technical possibilities of CSS Grid layout and CSS Subgrid (now available at this writing in Firefox Nightly)and how to make things better. Rachel is one of my favorite developers, her work has got me to experiment with Grid and now Subgrid and CSS as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have even purchased Perch for a site that I have (dormant but in development) her work, as well as husband Drew McLellan has always been inspiring. Everyone also got to see an appearance by Pixel the Cat as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bugs.chromium.org/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=762679&quot;&gt;Pushing for Subgrid in Chrome&lt;/a&gt; (go ahead, sign in and star it!), &lt;a href=&quot;https://noti.st/rachelandrew/aSEj0y/making-things-better-redefining-the-technical-possibilities-of-css#sRqusUa&quot;&gt;many technical aspects that you can see in Rachel&#39;s slides&lt;/a&gt; and many examples &lt;a href=&quot;https://gridbyexample.com/&quot;&gt;on Rachel&#39;s site&lt;/a&gt; but the best takeaway I found was Rachel&#39;s ending where she stated, “More than ever the web needs &lt;span class=&quot;bolder&quot;&gt;diversity of thought&lt;/span&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jen Simmons wrapped the day up with her talk on designing intrinsic layouts, solving layout designs, and even did a live coding walkthrough. Her work, along with Rachel&#39;s in regards to CSS Grid Layout, is the best. I point anyone who asks me where they can learn about Grid to those two wonderful people. Although you can do things the old fashioned way, and I still do from time-to-time, I like the direction that Grid and Flexbox are taking the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jen also mentioned that everything doesn&#39;t have to be done in Flexbox or Grid, that “good old fashioned stuff is still good.” I was fortunate enough to get a few minutes talking to Jen &lt;span class=&quot;italic&quot;&gt;(Thank you so very much!)&lt;/span&gt; about a few questions I had and as with all the speakers I spoke to and had questions with, she was so very gracious with her time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, as to how it was the last two years, Day One was stellar. I had a great time absorbing all the information, putting it into my logbook for future use and how I may do things at work going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-two&quot;&gt;Day Two&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kate O&#39;Neill kicked off Day Two with her great talk about the “Design of Meaning for the Future of Humanity”. About building our best tech, which hit home with me at my job. Our app can and needs to do a lot better. I took a lot from her talk for sure. Our app is what I call “Get in and get done”, so tedious at times so I can imagine what the customers and users think, which is a huge part of what Gerry McGovern spoke about on Day Three, but more on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meaningful design experiences is something I never had cross my mind and Kate certainly opened my mind up to that by using the Amazon Go Stores as an example. While a fantastic use of technology, you can go in, do your shopping, checkout and go (no pun intended), there is something you don&#39;t see in a Go store that you see in a regualr old supermarket. Taking an item off a shelf to help another person should they need it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to my height (6´3˝), I have had elderly people ask me to reach something on the top shelf for them and I was able to help with no problem or issue. I guess you can&#39;t do that in an Amazon Go store as it wont be registered correctly. So is this a meaningful experience? Dare I say, nay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A talk I was itching to hear, &lt;a href=&quot;https://rwt.io/&quot;&gt;Jason Pamental&lt;/a&gt; followed up with his talk on Dynamic Typographic Systems and Variable Fonts. Something I want to inject and use in both personal and work projects. This is and can be the now and the future!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason explained so succinctly on how you can have one font to rule them all (so to speak). One font file for one font family. You dont need one file for each font and it improves dramatically on the site performance exponentially, offering more styling options, decreasing load times, HTTP requests, and site font file sizes. Jason served up many examples of fonts, sites for variable fonts, &lt;a href=&quot;https://fontofthemonth.club/&quot;&gt;fontofthemonth.club&lt;/a&gt;, and was so very gracious in answering a few questions for me and offering up some help which I can use when it comes time to implement variable fonts on my site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sara Soueidan is someone I have been wishing to hear speak and I was jubilant in hearing Sara was going to be speaking in Boston this year and Sara followed up with a phenomenal talk on SVG Filters. A topic I have been looking more and more into. Her talk was fantastic! She has a ton of great content on SVG!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technical aspects are a lot to go into here, but I would suggest following Sara for any and all information she shares regarding SVG&#39;s. I was blown away and left wanting more! Even the parts that were above my comprehension, I just wanted to hear and learn more! &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sarasoueidan.com/&quot;&gt;Be sure to read up on her site for a lot of great articles and information&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah Parmenter followed the lunch break with her talk on “Designing for Personalities”. Every year Sarah had been at AEA Boston, I had missed her talks due to life happening. This year, I was so very grateful and fortunate to finally hear and see her speak and it was fantastic. A word (along with phenomenal) which I will probably use &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt;. It made me think of how my work can adjust our app and website to meet the needs and wishes of our customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah&#39;s examples, especally the Bloom &amp;amp; Wild example were perfect examples of customers to opt-out of newsletters and emails, Sarah&#39;s feedback was the catalyst for change when it came to opting out of emails on Mother&#39;s Day when someone had suffered a loss or tragedy. This talk brought me back to Eric&#39;s talk (and his book with Sara Wachter-Boettcher “&lt;em&gt;Designing for Real Life&lt;/em&gt;”) on Design for Real Life. This was widely acclaimed on social media and even in the British press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brad Frost followed with the technical side of design systems and again this year, did not disappoint. Brad, along with Dan Mall, the one-two punch for design systems, provided a great hour of if you got the product then you have the need for a design system. Which we do at work. The need for one that we do not have one at all for our app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan followed with how my role with the design system can be the most efficient it could be. I talked with both of them about how to get started and how I can make a design system from nothing that will do the job it needs to do for the company I work for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Brad and Dan were, and are, great to talk to about this topic. They provided me with answers to my questions. They touched on how you don&#39;t have to go guns-a-blazing and try to do everything in a design syste at once. Start off small, meet the needs and boundaries of what you&#39;re doing and go from there. Run your design system and it&#39;s evolution in tandem witht he project you or you and your team are currently working on. I even won a prize during &lt;strong&gt;“Name That Design System!”&lt;/strong&gt; (A small victory).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That wrapped up a busy Day Two in which my head was overflowing with ideas and information. Then it was onward to…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-three&quot;&gt;Day Three&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The accessibility rock block! Starting off with Michael Austin Sui discussing how (most passionately as well as eloquently) we&#39;re not designing in ways that are accessible to all. That even the smallest things are being overlooked. Something that really sticks with me and will continue to do so for as long as I am designing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael discussed AirBNB&#39;s approach to inclusive design. The best quote from Michael was “Design systems are your leverage to do better.” and that “Colors project differently on different devices.” couldn&#39;t have rang more true. When shown a slide of four different devices with the same hex code and four different shades of that hex color. I had a lot to take back to the office just in Michael&#39;s talk (a.k.a. Safari Dude) alone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marcy Sutton followed with her talk about CSS techniques and what they mean for accessibility and browser support. How some techniques can impact accessibility in ways that are unexpected, such as the &lt;code&gt;:focus&lt;/code&gt; pseudo class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markup order versus visual order of elements when using layouts such as Flexbox and CSS Grid, for example. A surprising example is that the Space Jam website, that is &lt;strong&gt;still&lt;/strong&gt; online, is more accessible than the Captain Marvel site tht is online from only this year. Amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking care when using Flexbox to change the UI presentation of the tab order of your elements, the first rule of ARIA is not to use it, and a plethora of other tidbits I took with me to better my CSS techniques!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derek Featherstone talked about inclusive design, a topic that is important to me. The main question I got out of Derek&#39;s talk was, “Are my design decisions and processes inclusive enough?” and my answer was a resounding “No”. I must do better during the projects I work on to make sure that I am being as inclusive as I can be and then take that ten giant steps further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is what we are doing as a design and development community as a whole, doing an effective enough job to include persons with impairments. We played a game, we had to create an inclusive game of Twister. It was thought provoking to say the least. I came up with an idea to include someone with an impairment, yet failed to figure out a solution for the spinner which goes to show I have a long way and a lot to learn so as to be more inclusive with my methods and designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we go about making our tools and methods for collaborating acceptable for people with different types of impairments. The example of the Xbox Adaptive Controller was a fantastic example of how it is done. From the packaging right down to the controller itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason Grigsby then took the stage to talk about web forms and “touched” (pardon the bad pun) on Face and Touch ID, password managers (I use LastPass and have used Dashlane and KeePass). Performed some “slight of hand” and stunned the crowd with his digital prestidigitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason spoke about Autofill and WebAuthn and also talked about the Payment Request and Credential Management API&#39;s and alluded to the fact we need to offer more than just passwords as a solution to the problem of more than half (51%) of users have a go to password, a favorite if you will, and an astounding 65% of passwords users use are used on more than one site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code example of the &lt;code&gt;ui-mask&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;maxlength&lt;/code&gt; and how, for instance, a year field takes only 2 numbers, but should take 4 numbers for the whole year, was enlightening. It was a great look into something that perhaps my company needs to (this will meet with MUCH resistance, this I know) implement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gerry McGovern closed out yet another great conference. Gerry always puts on a great and highly entertaining talk. This and last years conference were a testament to that. Gerry spoke about focusing on your users, taking your users feedback and going to task on adjusting your design to their feedback as to work with them and design with them for your product. Know your users!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google, the UK government, and AirBNB were some examples of gradual design that improved. Something yet again my company should look into but might be met with much resistance. In the three plus years at my company, I feel we do not take enough (if any) feedback from our users. Which is a huge mistake. I am pitching hard that we start to do this better. Gerry&#39;s talk just reinforced my feelings on user feedback to better the design of our system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-summary&quot;&gt;The Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, this year was a year I was going to try and be a lot more social. I still have a ways to go, all-in-all I was able to shed my insecurities and I was able to mingle, ask a lot of questions, and get over my anxiety over approaching people and talking to them. I got to see a lot of folks I met in 2018 and say hello.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met some nice people, talked with a few, had breakfast and lunch with speakers and attendees alike that were and are very nice and pleasant folks who like myself, come to learn from the best and I hope to see them next year as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Typetura</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/typetura/"/>
		<updated>2019-06-14T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/typetura/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I found this nice tool on Twitter (exactly where escapes me) and I had tinkered around with it and found it very useful. I haven&#39;t used it in production or development when it comes to my projects, but I know that someone could make great use of it somewhere, which is why I am posting this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://typetura.com/&quot;&gt;Typetura&lt;/a&gt; is (taken from the website) a fluid typesetting tool. Select a breakpoint and then use the style panel to add style to your page. Simple as that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can edit, add text (paragraphs, headings, lists and blockquotes), and tinker with the fonts with many CSS font properties. Take it for a spin, it&#39;s still in beta and the creators, Scott Kellum and Sal Hernandez, are still adding features and killing bugs. They&#39;re also taking questions and feedback. The info for that is right on the website.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>An Introduction to the Cascade</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/an-introduction-to-the-cascade/"/>
		<updated>2019-06-15T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/an-introduction-to-the-cascade/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is just an introduction in a condensed form. Just a minor basic level overview of the cascade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/css-cascade-4/#cascading&quot;&gt;The CSS Cascade Level 4 Spec states&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/an-introduction-to-the-cascade/CSS%20Cascade%20Level%204%20Spec&quot;&gt;The cascade takes a unordered list of declared values for a given property on a given element, sorts them by their declaration’s precedence, and outputs a single cascaded value.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an order in which selectors are prioritized. Importance, scope, specificity, and order. Let&#39;s go over each priority starting with importance. You don&#39;t have to take it all in at once. Break down each part until you understand it and then move on to the next section. I have provided code examples along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;importance&quot;&gt;Importance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An &lt;code&gt;!important&lt;/code&gt; declaration takes precedence over a normal declaration. Such as when the star selector is used for site-wide styling, take for instance &lt;code&gt;box-sizing: border-box;&lt;/code&gt; and then the same property (in this case below, &lt;code&gt;background-color&lt;/code&gt;) is using it in the case of the &lt;code&gt;body&lt;/code&gt; selector. So &lt;code&gt;background-color: red !important;&lt;/code&gt; will overrule the &lt;code&gt;background-color: white;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token selector&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; white&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token selector&quot;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; red &lt;span class=&quot;token important&quot;&gt;!important&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transition declarations &lt;code&gt;transition-timing-function: steps(6, end);&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;transition: all .25s ease-in-out;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Important user agent declarations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token selector&quot;&gt;input, textarea, keygen, select, button, meter, progress&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;-webkit-writing-mode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; horizontal-tb &lt;span class=&quot;token important&quot;&gt;!important&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Important user declarations &lt;code&gt;p { text-indent: 1em !important; }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Important author declarations &lt;code&gt;p { text-indent: 1.5em !important; }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Animation declarations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token atrule&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token rule&quot;&gt;@keyframes&lt;/span&gt; slide-right&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token selector&quot;&gt;50%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;margin-left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; 110px&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;opacity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; 0.9&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token selector&quot;&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;margin-left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; 200px&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normal author declarations &lt;code&gt;p { text-indent: 1.5em; }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normal user declarations &lt;code&gt;p { text-indent: 1em; }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normal user agent declarations &lt;code&gt;keygen, select { border-radius: 5px; }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/css-cascade-4/#biblio-css-transitions-1&quot;&gt;Transition declarations&lt;/a&gt; here.&lt;br&gt;
Read more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/css-cascade-4/#biblio-css-animations-1&quot;&gt;Animation declarations&lt;/a&gt; here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;scope&quot;&gt;Scope&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A declaration can be scoped to a subtree so that it only affects its scoping element and that element’s descendants. An example is &lt;code&gt;html&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;body&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/an-introduction-to-the-cascade/CSS%20Cascading%20and%20Inheritance%20Level%204&quot;&gt;If the scoping elements of two declarations have an ancestor/descendant relationship, then for normal rules the declaration whose scoping element is the descendant wins, and for important rules the declaration whose scoping element is the ancestor wins.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in other words, for normal declarations the inner scope&#39;s declarations override but for the &lt;code&gt;!important&lt;/code&gt; rule the outer scope&#39;s declarations override. Later wins over earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token selector&quot;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; red&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;/* This one wins */&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token selector&quot;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; green&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;/* This one wins due to specificity */&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token selector&quot;&gt;.title__heading&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;font-size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; 2em&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token selector&quot;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token property&quot;&gt;font-size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; 2.8em&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/an-introduction-to-the-cascade/MDN%20Web%20Docs&quot;&gt;One thing you should bear in mind when considering all this cascade theory, and what styles get applied over other styles, is that all this happens at the property level — properties override other properties, but you don&#39;t get entire rules overriding other rules. When several CSS rules match the same element, they are all applied to that element. Only after that are any conflicting properties evaluated to see which individual styles will win over others.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Learn/CSS/Introduction_to_CSS/Cascade_and_inheritance#A_note_on_rule_mixing&quot;&gt;A not on rule mixing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;specificty&quot;&gt;Specificty&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inline styles (anything between &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;style&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/style&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ID selectors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classes / pseudo-selectors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type selectors (for example, &lt;code&gt;h1&lt;/code&gt;) &amp;amp; pseudo-elements (&lt;code&gt;::before&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;order&quot;&gt;Order&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last declaration in document order wins. The order in which you load your stylesheets actually matters. If you’ve got two stylesheets linked in the head of your HTML document, the second stylesheet will override rules in the first stylesheet. This is why resets and &lt;code&gt;@imports&lt;/code&gt; are loaded before anything else in the main stylesheet you are using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have seen a lot of folks frustrated that they don&#39;t understand CSS. Some of animosity towards learning it, some disdain towards it. Knowing the cascade benefits the developer. The fundamental knowing of the cascade and how the cascade works will benefit you in the long run. I offer you some suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spec may look daunting and the language may look foreign, but when it comes down to it, it really isn&#39;t. If I can get it, from reading the spec then anyone can get it. There are some brilliant folks out there who knows JavaScript like the back of their hand. When it comes to CSS and the cascade, they say that it is a concept they cannot fully grasp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learn best by breaking things down to their core. Piece by piece. Breaking the cascade down to bits and pieces (just think of Atomic Design - Atoms, Molecules, Organisms) and dissecting those until I fully grasp the concept(s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have stumbled across this article and have any questions, feel free to use the contact page form and send me a question. I hope this article shed a little bit of light on the cascade for at least one person.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Carbon</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/carbon/"/>
		<updated>2019-06-15T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/carbon/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I came across Carbon on Twitter (exactly where escapes me. Again.) when I came across a tweet where there was code shared via Carbon. I thought it was pretty cool and a great way to share code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://carbon.now.sh/&quot;&gt;Carbon&lt;/a&gt; is (taken from the website) where you can “create and share beautiful images of your source code.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/carbon/Carbon&quot;&gt;You know all of those code screenshots you see on Twitter? Although the code&#39;s usually impressive, we saw room for improvement in the aesthetic department. Carbon is the easiest way to create beautiful images of your source code. So what are you waiting for? Go impress all of your followers with your newfound design prowess.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plain and simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can set the color scheme of the image where it uses themes from zsh and terminal color themes, the language you want to use (CSS, Clojure, Twig, Vue, etc.) and wish to share, there are different presets and you can customize the image, with options to tweet it or export it using some different settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want an easy way to share code snippets, this is the way!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Why Your Site Must Be Accessible</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/why-your-site-must-be-accessible/"/>
		<updated>2019-06-17T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/why-your-site-must-be-accessible/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Accessibility: &lt;em&gt;adj. that can be used, entered, reached, etc.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of us all too often forget how easy it is for us able-bodied persons to access the web. We don&#39;t need screen readers, assistive software, optical character recognition (OCR), adaptive or on-screen keyboards, magnification software. I could go on and on but you probably get the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We able-bodied people are fortunate. As of 2010, 56.7 million people in the United States had a disability of some kind and around 38.3 million people had a severe disability. That&#39;s 95 million people out of (as of 2010) around 309 million people. That&#39;s over a quarter of the entire populace, 30.7% to be precise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-that-have-to-do-with-me%3F&quot;&gt;What does that have to do with me?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A: Everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As designers and even developers, we &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; take into consideration that 30.7% of the population, there shouldn&#39;t be &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; argument about it. It&#39;s 2019 folks, time to get inclusive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;there&#39;s-that-word-%22inclusive%22&quot;&gt;There&#39;s that word &amp;quot;inclusive&amp;quot;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, and it&#39;s here to stay. As of 2016, it was the UN that declared;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/why-your-site-must-be-accessible/UN%20Universal%20Declaration%20of%20Human%20Rights,%20Article%2019&quot;&gt;Everyone has the right to freedom of opinion and expression; this right includes freedom to hold opinions without interference and to seek, receive and impart information and ideas through any media and regardless of frontiers.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we must be inclusive. The UN also added;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/why-your-site-must-be-accessible/UN%20Universal%20Declaration%20of%20Human%20Rights,%20Section%2032&quot;&gt;The promotion, protection and enjoyment of human rights on the Internet&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to not make a site accessible, is denying someone of their basic human right. A site that is slow and takes forever to load on a device that is 10 years old but still functions on a 2G/3G network is denying someone of their basic human right. You&#39;ll be surprized how many people access the internet from places you couldn&#39;t and don&#39;t even think of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accessibility is part of the fabric now, it is part of an inclusive experience for those that deserve it. The keyword there is &lt;em&gt;deserve&lt;/em&gt;. Don&#39;t get me wrong, the web is for everyone regardless of age, sex, religion, preferences, gender, color, or creed. I find that some folks just blow off disabled persons. Even if the disability is just a temporary one. Broken arm. Eye surgery. Child on your lap. Yes, those are temporary, situational or conditional disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-do-i-need-to-do%3F&quot;&gt;What Do I Need To Do?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The use of descriptive alt tags.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just having an alt tag of a boat that says “boat” isn&#39;t good enough. How about “Picture of a boat, a lobster boat coming into dock with a full haul from a day of hauling traps off the Maine coast.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keyboard navigation and Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check your site to see if you can navigate with the keyboard. All form fields, navigation items, links, buttons and modal dialogues/lightboxes should be accessible without using the mouse. There is some extra steps users with Macs have to take when enabling keyboard navigation in OSX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also enhance &lt;code&gt;:focus&lt;/code&gt; indicators and make them stand out and distinctive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Form fields&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure form fields have &lt;code&gt;aria-required=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; so they are read by screen readers as required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Closed captioning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure all videos are closed captioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basic ARIA landmarks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;role&lt;/code&gt; properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table tags&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markup all tables, cells, headers, and captions appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These just aren&#39;t it, there is a lot more you can do to make your site accessible that I won&#39;t be covering here but you can go through these links and read on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soap.stanford.edu/getting-started/basic-checks&quot;&gt;Stanford - Online Accessibility Program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://karlgroves.com/2013/09/05/the-6-simplest-web-accessibility-tests-anyone-can-do&quot;&gt;Karl Groves - The 6 Simplest Web Accessibility Tests Anyone Can Do&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://webaim.org/blog/10-easy-accessibility-tips/&quot;&gt;WebAIM - 10 Easy Accessibility Tips Anyone Can Use&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/test-evaluate/preliminary/&quot;&gt;W3C - Easy Checks - A First Review of Web Accessibility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.paciellogroup.com/resources/&quot;&gt;Resources - The Paciello Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot you can do. Do it. Educate yourself, read up on articles, attend conferences, workshops, talk to the speakers there. Soak in all you can about accessibility. You will gain a vast amount of information and in my case, education about accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are at a job where it is an uphill battle to get your company to recognize and practice accessibility, fight for it. Diplomatically. Push hard, but not too hard. Know your limits. I&#39;ll share from my experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We don&#39;t need to have accessibility as a priority.&amp;quot; said my boss. All I had to say is, &amp;quot;Yes we do.&amp;quot; I presented one story about why accessibility is important to someone who is focused on company. &amp;quot;Did you hear about Target being sued for their website not being accessible according to the ADA?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attitudes change when you tell suits how they can save money by not paying extra. &amp;quot;If the company gets sued for not adhereing to the ADA, it could cost a few thousand to a million or more to have a company come in and do an audit. I can make sure this doesn&#39;t happen while building the website.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s funny when you present suits that information how fast they give the green light and the go ahead to &amp;quot;do what you need to do. Make it happen.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be inclusive with your websites, your apps, your designs and remember those who aren&#39;t like you when you design and build great things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You got this.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Fear and Accessibility</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/fear-and-accessibility/"/>
		<updated>2019-08-22T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/fear-and-accessibility/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;fear-of-the-unknown&quot;&gt;Fear of the Unknown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the recent court appeal to the US Supreme Court with a certain pizza conglomerate, “Dom Inos” I’ll call them, against blind persons, I have been thinking of what could drive a corporation to do something so egregious that it brings about the need for me to voice my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What causes people and companies, to forego accessibility for greed and because “it is not necessary”. What could it be? Fear. In my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What company hires people to pump out sites that are dependency-laden, framework-driven, and plastered with all the new-fangled, shiny new technologies of the month? 85-95% is my guess. Those companies in turn set deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those deadlines are hard deadlines that need to be met, or else. Those deadlines are met, but sacrificing things such as accessibility audits, accessibility checks, color contrast checks, motion checks if the site is animated more than a Looney Tunes cartoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies fear having to go back and spend money to fix what isn’t compliant. Even if it is a pithy percentage of what their yearly revenue is. In the case of “Dom Inos”, it’s less than 0.000000001%. A drop in the bucket. Why fight it? Fear. (Greed also). They don’t want to be the company that sets a precedent legally and their brand tanks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEO’s with absolutely ZERO technical skills, backgrounds, and minimal technical abilities. (I can use Outlook is not a technical skill). “Someone else will handle that, I won’t get my hands dirty if something bad happens. I can pass the buck off and act like I had no idea.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-about-%E2%80%A6%3F&quot;&gt;What about …?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, fear. “Conner doesn’t know WCAG AA accessibility guidelines. We don’t have the time to have him learn because we push this out tomorrow.” is the line I’ve heard while at three different places where I was doing front end development. (All names are not insinuating anyone with the names I have used as examples).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What is a contrast checker? Why do we need to check the color contrast of this website? This is going to eat up precious dev time!” or the best one, “Tanner is our CTO and he says that we don’t have disabled people coming to the site.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or the brogrammers who exclaim accessibility is a “nice-to-have” but not necessary. Or some who say not even necessary at all! The CSS-in-JS home boys that stack a color: red; in a quagmire of div tags as far as the eye can see!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, accessibility by all is a right, not a convenience for individuals, companies, or corporations to ignore. The web is a human right, so says the United Nations. (No, really, look it up Chad!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fear of not knowing. Fear of having to spend money. Fear of having to ask for help when doing. Fear of losing precious development time playing in the JS framework playground to hammer out a sparkly new cool feature or wicked awesome animation for the site when a user scrolls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;800 companies were sued in 2017 and Tanner’s company could be next. Fear needs to be in that developers need to be held accountable. Bottom line. If you don’t make it accessible, then there are ramifications. It looks like those numbers will be met in 2019, if not exceeded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/fear-and-accessibility/Bruce%20Lawson&quot; class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;The rate of lawsuits filed in federal courts related to website and app accessibility has now hit a rate of one-an-hour, that’s 8 a day, 40 per week and set to be on pace for over 2,000 lawsuits again this year.&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/eNwUpsFQtH&quot;&gt;https://t.co/eNwUpsFQtH&lt;/a&gt;&amp;mdash; Bruce Lawson (@brucel) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/brucel/status/1164829479010590720?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;August 23, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-do-we-go-from-here%3F&quot;&gt;Where do we go from here?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not difficult. If I can do it… if I can convince companies I have worked with and firms, and individuals… learning how to do it is one of the most simple (and for me, solely speaking, easiest) thing developers can do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is will the lazy web do it? Or will we just keep rolling out more inaccessible sites or applications keeping people off a platform that they deserve every right to be able to access. Hence the term “accessibility”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not rocket science folks, it’s a right. Let’s make it so the web is all-inclusive, not a resort for the privileged brogrammers who are white males, no impairments or disabilities, who are ordering pizzas off the “Dom Inos” app and playing fantasy football on their favorite sports website in their man caves.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>CORS, CodePen &amp; Me</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/cors-codepen-and-me/"/>
		<updated>2019-09-05T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/cors-codepen-and-me/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;cors%2C-codepen-and-me&quot;&gt;CORS, CodePen and Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been experimenting and leaning about Variable Fonts ever since &lt;a href=&quot;https://rwt.io/&quot;&gt;Jason Pamental&lt;/a&gt; spoke at An Event Apart this past May in Boston. I had been following Jason as well as Mandy Michael and Scott Kellum’s works/tweets/articles/talks as well. All great stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was (and still am very much so) intrigued, as I am with most everything spoken about at conferences, in using variable fonts for not only my site but for work projects as well. When &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethanmarcotte.com/&quot;&gt;Ethan Marcotte&lt;/a&gt; coined “responsive web design” I wondered shortly afterwards, “I wonder if fonts and typography will be soon to follow?” Well, much to my delight it did!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a pen on my CodePen account, the heading was not showing for me but forked pen by Jason had it coming in quite nicely. I had tried to get the pens to render the variable fonts I had tried to use for over a month with no success because I did not know about the CORS issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORS, or Cross-Origin Resource Sharing, is, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/CORS&quot;&gt;MDN&lt;/a&gt; (Mozilla Developer Network);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/cors-codepen-and-me/MDN&quot;&gt;a mechanism that uses additional HTTP headers to tell a browser to let a web application running at one origin (domain) have permission to access selected resources from a server at a different origin. A web application executes a cross-origin HTTP request when it requests a resource that has a different origin (domain, protocol, or port) than its own origin.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, unbeknownst to me, browsers restrict cross-origin HTTP requests initiated from within scripts. &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/CORS&quot;&gt;To quote from MDN again&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/cors-codepen-and-me/MDN&quot;&gt;This means that a web application using those APIs can only request HTTP resources from the same origin the application was loaded from, unless the response from the other origin includes the right CORS headers.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had tweeted out to Jason if he could take a peek and see what the issue was because I was still unaware of the CORS issue until Scott Kellum (@ScottKellum) tweeted at me about it. So I went right to the search engine (DuckDuckGo for this guy) and did a search which came up with some good stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-did-i-solve-it%3F&quot;&gt;How did I solve it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best (and easiest) solution I found came from here &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2U2DV5s&quot;&gt;http://bit.ly/2U2DV5s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in the netlify.toml file, I just implemented these headers;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;[[headers]]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;for = &quot;/&lt;span class=&quot;token italic&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token content&quot;&gt;.woff&quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;[headers.values]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;Access-Control-Allow-Origin = &quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;Content-Type = &quot;application/font-woff&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;[[headers]]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;for = &quot;/&lt;span class=&quot;token italic&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token content&quot;&gt;.woff2&quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;[headers.values]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;Access-Control-Allow-Origin = &quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;Content-Type = &quot;application/font-woff2&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-markdown&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;[[headers]]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;for = &quot;/&lt;span class=&quot;token italic&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token content&quot;&gt;.ttf&quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;[headers.values]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;Access-Control-Allow-Origin = &quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight-line&quot;&gt;Content-Type = &quot;application/font-ttf&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And went to test and they worked! It took about 15 minutes of searching and reading and only less than 5 minutes of placing the appropriate code in and pushing it live!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is a better, or easier way to implement this, I would be very interested in knowing and learning. The other ways involved a little bit of in-depth command line work and I’m not knocking those methods (nor would I be scared to do them) but this one just seemed a lot easier for what I was trying to accomplish was for me to be able to see the variable font I was calling off my site in CodePen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;special-thanks&quot;&gt;Special Thanks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/@jpamental&quot;&gt;Jason Pamental - @jpamental&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/@ScottKellum&quot;&gt;Scott Kellum - @ScottKellum&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/@sarah_edo&quot;&gt;Sarah Drasner - @sarah_edo&lt;/a&gt; for their guidance and assistance!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Open House</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/open-house/"/>
		<updated>2019-10-17T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/open-house/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I finally am getting around to writing again after not having written for some time. This is about my adventure down to &lt;a href=&quot;https://djr.com/&quot;&gt;David Jonathan Ross&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s home in Conway, Massachusetts for an open house. It was a great weekend full of adventure and meeting people I normally wouldn&#39;t have, talking typography and fonts, and watching some very cool and extremely awesome rpesentations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tour around town was nice. Conway is a quaint little town in Western Massachusetts. A night of fun and discussion followed on the first night there. A tour of the historical society looking at all the pieces there was very interesting, and the pizza at the local bar was excellent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the presentations were great on the second day. As well as the early morning apple picking and tour around the immediate area. Some maple flavored soft serve ice cream at Hager&#39;s Farm Stand, driving around the area and looking at the very beautiful scenery, some excellent apples at Apex Orchards and getting to know some folks there a little was what the doctor ordered for the beginnings of burnout that I was experiencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was made even better by meeting Scott Kellum, Sal Hernandez and Ana Monroe from &lt;a href=&quot;https://typetura.com/&quot;&gt;Typetura&lt;/a&gt; of whom have created one of the best typographical resources on the web today with Typetura. The site looks great as well and I wish them all the luck going forward and much success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking a bit with DJR was a pleasure. Since I started getting into learning about variable fonts, I was suggested to visit his site for fonts all of which are so finely crafted. His studio is amazing as well as his work. A welcoming host and extremely gracious one at that. It was a pleasure being able to go down and be out of my element for a weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pleasant surprise was getting to catch up with &lt;a href=&quot;https://rwt.io/&quot;&gt;Jason Pamental&lt;/a&gt; again before another get together in &lt;a href=&quot;https://aneventapart.com/event/denver-2019&quot;&gt;Denver at An Event Apart&lt;/a&gt;. I was also taken aback by a very generous invite which I won&#39;t reveal until after the conference and I get back, decompress and write about the week. Suffice it to say, it is something that I am absolutely gobsmacked that I am able to do, and even though I never thought it would ever happen, I can put it on my bucket list and cross it off. I am forever indebtted and grateful to know Jason and call him a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the weekend. A great breakfast, some great conversation and as much as I would have loved to stay and taken a walk around town for the fair that was going on where we were, I had to drive four hours and the crowd of about thirty people were starting to disperse. I was able to get a picture with DJR and Jason, I was hoping to get Scott, Ana, and Sal for a group photo as well, but they had a long way to travel 8-9 hours back to Washington D.C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/breakfastphotoop.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;From left to right, Jason Pamental, Todd Libby, and David Jonathan Ross at breakfast Sunday morning&quot; class=&quot;content__image&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;An early morning breakfast photo op, fanboy moment. (L to R - Jason Pamental, myself, David Jonathan Ross)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/group-photo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A group photo at the attendees at David Jonathan Ross&#39;s open house. Photo taken at Apex Orchards, courtesy of Matthew Rechs&quot; class=&quot;content__image&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;and here is the group photo, courtesy of Matthew Rechs, taken at Apex Orchards&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall. I had a blast. I don&#39;t get out much and do thing like this. It is rare. It was great meeting people and getting to talk to folks outside the programming world (there were a few programmers there as well). For someone that feels like he is alone in a room full of people sometimes, I can say it helped my hesitation to do social things like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To DJR. Thank you for hosting a wonderful event and I hope to do it again at some point! I&#39;m grateful to have met you, talked with you, and your kindness was greatly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>An Event Apart 2019 - Denver Wrap-Up Edition, Part One</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-denver-2019-part-one/"/>
		<updated>2019-10-27T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-denver-2019-part-one/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-event-apart-denver-2019%2C-denver%2C-co&quot;&gt;An Event Apart Denver 2019, Denver, CO&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-day-before&quot;&gt;The Day Before&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got into Denver after seven hours of travel, and it had been thirty-two years since I had been here. It was snowing, which I could have waited on but still I was traveling again. I got to do something I never thought I would ever do and that was attend the speaker meeting prior to the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a huge bear hug from my new friend Jason Ogle, the man behind the &lt;a href=&quot;https://userdefenders.com/&quot;&gt;User Defenders Podcast&lt;/a&gt;. One of my favorites, I highly suggest folks subscribe, listen, join the User Defenders community and &lt;a href=&quot;https://patreon.com/userdefenders&quot;&gt;become a patron on Patreon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/jasono-todd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jason Ogle and Todd Libby&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;(L to R: Myself and Jason Ogle, creator of the User Defenders Podcast)The main reason why I traveled to Denver. This guy and the User Defenders Podcast.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to meet &lt;a href=&quot;https://miriam.codes/&quot;&gt;Miriam Suzanne&lt;/a&gt;, whom has been doing videos for Mozilla Developers, along with Jen Simmons on YouTube for some time now and it was a plesant surprise to see her there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to meet Sarah Drasner, and Phil Hawksworth whom work for Netlify. Which was also another pleasant surprise. I knew Sarah was a speaker there, but I did not know Netlify (as a sponsor) and Phil would be there. So I got some more laptop stickers and schwag from the Netlify table. Also a really nice Netlify t-shirt!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/sd-ph-tl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sarah Drasner, Phil Hawksworth and Todd Libby at the Netlify table at An Event Apart Denver&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;(L to R: Sarah Drasner, Myself and Phil Hawksworth, at the Netlify table in Denver at An Event Apart Denver.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably one of, if not the most awesome experiences of the trip was the speaker dinner. Now if you do not know, the speakers usually set aside the night before for dinner for the group. Something I thought I&#39;d never experience because I am not a speaker. Well, that all changed due, in part to Jason Pamental adding me as a +1 and I could not be more grateful to know Jason. An experience I will never forget and I had a phenomenal time. Talking with folks on the walk to the restaurant was the highlight of the day. Weary with travel, but excited being able to attend this event. Forever grateful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;day-one&quot;&gt;Day One&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://zeldman.com/&quot;&gt;Jeffrey Zeldman&lt;/a&gt; kicked it off with his talk on Slow Design for an Anxious World. I could listen to this talk over and over and over. Slowing the design down makes it more comprehensive for the reader. Slowing the design down so that readers can comprehend web pages and make better decisions. Learn to make layouts that help the user relax, sit back and enjoy the design, comprehension and engagement on a much less stressful level when web pages are either too slow or too fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/jz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jeffrey Zeldman on stage at An Event Apart Denver&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Jeffrey Zeldman on stage at An Event Apart Denver talking about Slow Design for an Anxious World.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/jp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jason Pamental on stage at An Event Apart Denver&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Jason Pamental on stage at An Event Apart Denver speaking about Dynamic Typographic Systems and Variable Fonts.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rwt.io/&quot;&gt;Jason Pamental&lt;/a&gt; navigated the land of Variable Fonts and Typography and as always, a super treat, Tristan and Tillie, his collies, are in his slides. Love the dog pictures and tweets! His talk included how developments in the field of typography and variable fonts make it easier to create robust, scalable typographic systems on the web. Fantastic stuff, phenomenal talk by someone I am grateful to call a friend. You should, if you love typography, or even if you don&#39;t and want to learn about typography and variable fonts, &lt;a href=&quot;https://rwt.io/newsletter&quot;&gt;subscribe to Jason&#39;s fantastic newsletter&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s well worth it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://trentwalton.com/&quot;&gt;Trent Walton&lt;/a&gt; spoke about the repercussions of using third parties when it comes to integrating such things as a commenting system or online fonts. How much can a website weigh without you knowing it and who is tracking us? Trent also took us through tools he uses and methods to see what a site is doing behind the scenes and reasons why to use apps like Ghostery. This always made me think a lot more when I first heard Trent&#39;s talk in Boston about all the bloat that comes with different third-party systems. Great refresher and the artwork from Trent&#39;s son was top notch!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/tw.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Trent Walton on stage at An Event Apart Denver&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;JTrent Walton discussing third-party scripts and services and the impact they can have on site performance.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even Trent&#39;s son, Charlie helped out with some of the slides. Of which were excellently done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/tw-art.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Trent Walton&#39;s son Charlie and his art, helped his dad out in his slides&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Trent&#39;s son Charlie helped out with the slide presentation and produced some excellent art for dad to show the crowd at An Event Apart&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meyerweb.com/&quot;&gt;Eric Meyer&lt;/a&gt; came up after lunch and talked about generated content. Pullquotes, blockquotes, gradients, &lt;code&gt;::before&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;::after&lt;/code&gt;. Lots of great stuff, some M*A*S*H theme music, and lots of CSS! Even an Under Construction redux using CSS. Those need to come back into style. Literally. Eric also spoke about what is good generated content, what can we do with it? How far can we push it? So much to think about when dealing with generated content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/em.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eric Meyer on stage at An Event Apart Denver&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Eric Meyer spoke about generated content, how it is good, what we can do with it and how far can we push it to create creative generted content and use it as a tool for everyday use.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rachelandrew.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Rachel Andrew&lt;/a&gt; followed with her &amp;quot;Making Things Better: Redefining the Technical Possibilities of CSS&amp;quot; talk. Flexbox, CSS Grid, Subgrid, some great looks at some of the current and future technical possibilities for developers and designers for creating things on the web. Multicol, Scroll snap, Subgrid. All things I am excited to implement. Page Layout was even mentioned and I didn&#39;t even remember that from her Boston talk. Rachel is one of a few when it comes to CSS and Grid Layout, who I consider the gold standards from learning from the other being the next speaker I&#39;ll be talking about below. Jen Simmons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/ra.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel Andrew on stage at An Event Apart Denver&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Rachel Andrew talked about what is coming to browsers soon, the technical aspects of what&#39;s coming down the road and what that means for CSS.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/js.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jen Simmons on stage at An Event Apart Denver&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Jen Simmons spoke to the crowd in Denver about creating accessible and reusable page and component layouts and how to create something we thought we could never do before.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jensimmons.com/&quot;&gt;Jen Simmons&lt;/a&gt; wrapped up the day of speakers with her phenomenal talk about Designing Intrinsic Layouts. Creating accessible, reusable and component layouts. The art of graphic design and how we can now do things on the web we only could dream about years prior. How to do a header real easy and simple in Grid and Flex. Jen always brings the good stuff with so many creative examples of her experiments on her own site as well. Jen&#39;s examples of layouts that are done in comparison to some of the things found in graphic arts posters and magazines is simply amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-user-defenders-podcast&quot;&gt;The User Defenders Podcast&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jason Ogle came to the stage with three speakers to do a live show of his User Defenders podcast. Joined by Mina Markham, Farai Madzima, and Derek Featherstone, they traversed many subjects in the hour such as inclusion, accessibility, and ethics. It was a pleasure and privilege to be there and to have helped out in a small way by recording video of the podcast. Terrific episode!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/udp.png&quot; alt=&quot;User Defenders Podcast live on stage at An Event Apart Denver. From Left to right, Derek Featherstone, Farai Madzima, Mina Markham and Jason Ogle sitting on stage on stools with a blue curtain backdrop. Photo courtesy of Jeffrey Zeldman&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;From Left to right, Derek Featherstone, Farai Madzima, Mina Markham and Jason Ogle sitting on stage on stools with a blue curtain backdrop talking during the live podcast of User Defenders hosted by Jason Ogle. Photo courtesy of Jeffrey Zeldman.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to help out and film video with my new iPhone 11 Pro Max in 4k, so I am anxious to see the video after all the editing is done and see how it came out. I was more than happy to have been able to help out Jason, who I consider now a good friend. If you&#39;re not subscribed to the User Defenders podcast, you are missing out! &lt;a href=&quot;https://userdefenders.com/subscribe/&quot;&gt;Go subscribe today&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dinner after with Jason Ogle, Jason Pamental, Derek Featherstone and Eric Meyer was at a place that was referred to me by a friend, the name of the place, iRamen+Fish. It was terrific. A lot of good food and great conversation. I had a great time. A definite highlight of the trip as well. I was glad they all came along for dinner with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/dinner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;From Left to right, Jason Pamental, Eric Meyer, Todd Libby, Jason Ogle, and Derek Featherstone sitting at a table at dinner in Denver, Colorado. Photo courtesy of Jason Ogle&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Dinner at iFish+Ramen with this terrific group of people that came out to dinner with me. Photo courtesy of Jason Ogle.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fantastic kickoff to the conference! I don&#39;t think it could have gotten any better than this. Dinner with some of the best people I have had the privilege to meet and get to know over the years. Every time I am at a conference with these folks I learn something new and have a good time doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the end of Day One. A day of learning, of friendship and of good food. &lt;a href=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-denver-2019-part-two/&quot;&gt;On to Day Two&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>An Event Apart 2019 - Denver Wrap-Up Edition, Part Two</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-denver-2019-part-two/"/>
		<updated>2019-10-28T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-denver-2019-part-two/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-event-apart-denver-2019%2C-denver%2C-co&quot;&gt;An Event Apart Denver 2019, Denver, CO&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;day-two&quot;&gt;Day Two&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/jc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Josh Clark on stage at An Event Apart Denver&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Josh Clark speaking on stage at An Event Apart Denver on machine learning and what it can do for humans.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bigmedium.com/&quot;&gt;Josh Clark&lt;/a&gt;, the Eleventh Strongest Man in Maine, started the day off talking about machines. Automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-denver-2019-part-two/Josh%20Clark&quot;&gt;How can we use technology in a way that adds meaning?&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it to have machine learning as a design material. What can machine learning do for us? How can we act on patterns we detect in machine learning and bringing them into the products we design and use. Slack, predictive keyboards, forms, survey tools. We can get cozy with casual uses of machine learning. I&#39;m also gunning for that tenth spot on the list Josh!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/jc-tl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Josh Clark and Todd Libby at An Event Apart Denver in the hallway posing for a photo.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Josh Clark on the left and Todd Libby on the right posing for a photo in the hallway at the Hilton Denver City Center at An Event Apart Denver 2019.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/bd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beth Dean on stage at An Event Apart Denver.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Beth Dean speaking at An Event Apart Denver on the impact technology and design has on social aspects of society and technology.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thebethdean.com/&quot;&gt;Beth Dean&lt;/a&gt; was next, speaking about Unsolved Problems. Talking about the impact of technology and the social impact it has. Design and the effects it has on people, places and things. Taking us through a walk through different places in the world and the designs done that help the social impact that benefits people and economies. Architectural designs that impact certain aspects of environments and places, what happens when designs are good and what happens when designs go bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/fm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;farai Madzima at An Event Apart Denver speaking on diversity and inclusion.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Farai Madzima at An Event Apart Denver speaking about inclusion and diversity and how to make design teams work together and make successful products. (Photo courtsey of Jason Ogle)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://faraimadzima.com/&quot;&gt;Farai Madzima&lt;/a&gt; spoke next about how design teams can  work well together to make products that make the company profitable and make the world a better place. How can we make our teams more diverse? How can we keep those people that are lost when the environments they are in aren&#39;t safe and they leave?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we make this industry more diverse and inclusive? All are fantastic questions and the answers are there in the future, but we&#39;re working on them now. Farai’s talk captured me, entranced me, and make me think. I need to stop and assist in the need for tech to make change. A phenomenal talk that I am super glad to have seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a pleasure and I am grateful to have met Farai, had a great disscussion with him at lunch and was able to be there for his talk.a11y&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/fm-tl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Farai Madzima and Todd Libby at An Event Apart Denver posing for a photo.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Farai Madzima on the left and Todd Libby on the right posing for a photo in the dining room at the Hilton Denver City Center at An Event Apart Denver 2019.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the lunch break, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lukew.com/&quot;&gt;Luke Wroblewski&lt;/a&gt; came to the stage and showed us how people use devices today and how design needs to adapt. people spend three hours a day on mobile app and there are four billion mobile devices out there. How conversion rates increased with certain companies when removing things that were bothersome or not needed when it came to mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/lw.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Luke Wroblewski on stage at An Event Apart Denver&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Luke Wroblewski on stage discussing how people use devices todya, mainly mobile devices and how design needs to adapt to the number of mobile devices used.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remove all friction that distracts the user from experiencing the product value, don&#39;t be afraid to educate contextually when it comes to successful onboarding. Get people to product value as soon as possible, but not faster. Edit distractions and teach in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was great to hear and see Luke again. The last time I had heard him speak was in Boston in 2008, it was also great to have been at the speaker dinner and had some great and hilarious conversation with him as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/mm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mina Markham on stage at An Event Apart Denver&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Mina Markham on stage discussing lots of great topics including progressive enhancement, design, accessibility, localization, and most importantly, inclusion.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mina.codes/&quot;&gt;Mina Markham&lt;/a&gt; then took the stage for Full-Featured Art Direction for the Web, creator of the Pantsuit UI Pattern Library for the Hilary Clinton campaign in 2016, Mina took us through progressive enhancement and little design changes that make for huge payoffs in the end design-wise. Localization is important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mina talked about localization on Slack and how it was rough at the beginning when the team was translating but not localizing. Inclusion and how art direction is inclusive. Very important to many, including myself and for crying out loud Beyonce! HIRE MINA MARKHAM! Mina also reminds us that not only is color contrast important for art and design, but for accessibility sake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/mm-tl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mina Markham and Todd Libby sitting on stage at An Event Apart Denver posing for the photo.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Mina Markham and Todd Libby posing for a photo sitting on stage at An Event Apart Denver after Mina&#39;s great talk.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we all took this photo op, seeing is I had the shirt (one of many colors) and Jen had the idea of taking this photo. Unfortunately Rachel wasn&#39;t feeling well and was unable to join us, but I hope one day to wear this with all five women and have that picture taken. That would be epic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/ms-tl-mm-js.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Miriam Suzanne, Todd Libby, Mina Markham, and Jen Simmons standing in the conference hall at An Event Apart Denver. Todd has his red Andrew&amp; Simmons&amp; Markham&amp; Soueidan&amp; Jina shirt on.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Miriam Suzanne, Todd Libby, Mina Markham, and Jen Simmons posing for a photo  at An Event Apart Denver.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To finish off Day Two was &lt;a href=&quot;https://danmall.me/&quot;&gt;Dan Mall&lt;/a&gt; talking about Putting the &#39;Design&#39; in Design Systems. A deep dive into design systems, again playing the &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Name That Design System&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; game show (which I &#39;won&#39; at Boston and did not participate in). I could listen to this talk again and again, as well as listen to Dan again and again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan explains it&#39;s not the components, it&#39;s about how they relate to each other. How to make your design system distinct, there are multiple design principles you can use, universal principles &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;accessible&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;simple&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/dm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dan Mall at An Event Apart Denver talking about Design Systems.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Dan Mall on stage discussing design systems at An Event Apart Denver.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan takes us through some of the most well-known design systems and how many components they have in our search for a comprehensive design system. They why&#39;s on why there are certain components with certain design systems. A great way to cap off another phenomenal day at An Event Apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farai&#39;s talk was the highlight of Day Two and the entire conference, in my opinion. That ws the enlightenment I had needed in my professional life, most definitely. Now... &lt;a href=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-denver-2019-part-three/&quot;&gt;on to Day Three. The final day!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>An Event Apart 2019 - Denver Wrap-Up Edition, Part Three</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-denver-2019-part-three/"/>
		<updated>2019-10-30T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/an-event-apart-denver-2019-part-three/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-event-apart-denver-2019%2C-denver%2C-co&quot;&gt;An Event Apart Denver 2019, Denver, CO&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;day-three---the-final-chapter&quot;&gt;Day Three - The Final Chapter&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never look forward to the final day because it’s the final day. With all good things however, they must come to an end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/ko.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kate O&#39;Neill at An Event Apart Denver speaking on human experience in technology.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Kate O&#39;Neill on stage discussing human experience in tech at An Event Apart Denver.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kate O&#39;Neill kicked off Day Three with human experiences in technology. Kate went into business objectives and what humans are trying to accomplish through those experiences. Building our best tech, grow our best businesses, and become our best selves. Kate touched on meaning and innovation as she spoke about things like Augmented Reality (AR), machine work, and technological capabilities. I was in Boston when Kate gave this talk and it was a good reminder to hear it again. Especially when she touched upon the Amazon Go store. People can&#39;t help other people get things off the shelf at an Amazon Go store, which takes the humanity out of the shopping experience creating a poor experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/sd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sarah Drasner at An Event Apart Denver talking about Animation on the Web.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Sarah Drasner on stage discussing Animation on the Web at An Event Apart Denver.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah Drasner took the stage after with &amp;quot;Animation on the Bleeding Edge&amp;quot;. Sarah spoke about emotions and how &amp;quot;the web is first and foremost about communicating&amp;quot;. She then showed everyone Nuxt and it is impeccable timing for me to be here as I am going to be (and I already am when I can) learning Vue.js. Showing animations in Vue 2 using GreenSock. This looks like something I could really enjoy learning for sure. Different types of animations and their responsive qualities, but then Sarah took us through responsiveness in 3D! This part of her talk was terrific. Some terrific, mind-blowing demos from Sarah making me want to learn Vue and Nuxt now. This was the first time I have seen and heard Sarah speak and it was truly as phenomenal as her slides of her artwork were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/sd-code.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Code snippets from Sarah Drasner&#39;s talk at An Event Apart Denver&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Code snippets from Sarah Drasner&#39;s talk at An Event Apart Denver.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Val Head came up with &amp;quot;Making Motion Inclusive&amp;quot; and started off with motion. Referring to the WCAG, Val took us through the guidelines. Flashing items, movement and animation within content that may be harmful (seizure inducing triggers) on the WCAG 2.0 AA &amp;amp; AAA levels. Val went into animation that affects folks with vestibular orders such as motion sickness and migraines. How those animations and things like parallax can physically make someone with a vestibular order (like myself) sick. Val then went into talking about &lt;code&gt;prefers-reduced-motion&lt;/code&gt;. Another talk I saw in Boston (that you can also read about in the archives) and another talk I was glad to hear again for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/vh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Val Head at An Event Apart Denver talking about Motion on the Web.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Val Head discussing motion on the web and making motion and animation accessible at An Event Apart Denver.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for lunch I decided to go out for lunch and meet up with my friend Chris DeMars. I asked if Jason Pamental wanted to go and he agreed and we met Chris at La Loma. Lunch was phenomenal. Not much time to spent, but time well spent indeed and good food, good conversation. Chris and I were supposed to go over to the General Assembly building and hear Eric Meyer talk on Tuesday night but the weather was not good at all and the event was cancelled, which was a bummer, but I got to hear a lot of great stuff this week. I was also bummed I wasn&#39;t able to hang out with Chris a bit longer than just lunch. Chris is also another excellent speaker, a guy that knows his stuff and is a champion for accessibility. His talk at UX Burlington got me fixated in a11y and the need to focus a lot more on that and keep that skill in my arsenal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/cd-tl-jp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;(From left to right, Chris DeMars, Todd Libby, and Jason pamental at La Loma in Denver at lunch posing for a photo.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;(From L to R) Chris DeMars, Todd Libby, and Jason pamental at lunch at La Loma in Denver inbetween breaks at lunch having a great time catching up during a great lunch.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at the conference, Derek Featherstone kicked off the last half of the final day with &amp;quot;Inclusive, by Design&amp;quot;. We need to think in more diverse ways with regards to accessibility and to think of these things by default. Derek walked us through case studies and inclusion on the web and with web apps. If we include people with disabilities in the process, things will be much better. &amp;quot;Acknowledge your privilege, and your power, and your position in the design process.&amp;quot; says Derek. &amp;quot;Ask &#39;How can we make sure that we include more people with disabilities earlier and more meaningfully in the process?&amp;quot; Derek had a lot of questions that we need to ask ourselves to be more inclusive in designs and the design process, and to include people with disabilities in that process. This is another talk I have heard, again in Boston. Well worth hearing and seeing it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/df.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Derek Featherstone at An Event Apart Denver discussion Inclusive Design and Accessiblity.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Derek Featherstone discussing Inclusive Design and Accessibility on stage at An Event Apart Denver.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/gm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gerry McGovern wrapping up the conference at An Event Apart Denver discussing Delivering Products. Pointing at the screen with a slide from a Google Search and how ridiculous it can be.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Gerry McGovern wrapping up the conference at An Event Apart Denver discussing Delivering Products. Don&#39;t miss a talk from Gerry, they&#39;re not only informative, but very entertaining!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and as with the last few AEA events I have attended, Gerry McGovern ended the conference with his stellar (and very humorous) talk, &amp;quot;Delivering Product 67&amp;quot;. I just finished Gerry&#39;s book &amp;quot;Top Tasks&amp;quot; and it was brilliant. I have applied things in that book to the company I work for to better our product. Humility, Agility, and Simplicity. Gerry shows us how to enhance those qualities to support our company&#39;s business and advance our careers. Master the metrics of customer simplicity. I had the pleasure and privilege to have a couple of great conversations over breakfast with Gerry and he is a delight to speak with. All the speakers are! (More on that later). How to keep the garbage off of our pages, stopping the customer from doing what they really need to do. There is too much garbage on the web. Gerry points this out with the many iterations of the Google homepage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with that, the conference was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-after-conference&quot;&gt;The After-Conference&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consider myself fortunate, lucky, and pretty damn grateful. With that said, I got to hang out with Jason Pamental and Miriam Suzanne and a new conference friend for some time, eating Indian cuisine at a local place Miriam took us too nearby, then hanging out at the restaurant at the hotel and talking for hours. During the way, I had met TJ Pitre and we got to talking as well. This is why I enjoy the conferences I go to. I meet a mix of people far and wide. I don&#39;t want to meet the same people over and over and over who are like me. Which is why I strongly advocate for diversity and inclusion. Which is why Farai&#39;s talk hit me at the very core.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/denver.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A view of downtown Denver on 16th Street with all the tall buildings and people walking around on a cold day after three days of snow.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;A view of downtown Denver on 16th Street.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some lengthy conversation I retired to my room and then prepared to rest for the long trek back home. I really don&#39;t like the end process after the conferences because I meet so many great people and talk to some very smart folks in the course of three days (even more because I get there a day early and stay a day late).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/hotel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A view of the hotel from an area in the lobby that folks can relax and do remote work from in a small meeting area on the main lobby floor showing a cup of Starbucks coffee next to my MacBook Pro looking out at the street from the hotel into downtown Denver.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;A view of my workstation setup in the meeting area on the main floor of the Denver City Center Hilton looking out towards the street to downtown.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a designer or developer, or in web of any kind, you MUST go to An Event Apart. Whether it is in your city or whether you have to travel. It is well worth it. A conference that is diverse and inclusive, no egos, and all the learning and camraderie you can find all in one place. To get your boss(es) to pay for you and/or your team to go, &lt;a href=&quot;https://aneventapart.com/why-attend&quot;&gt;go here and read about all the things said&lt;/a&gt; and don&#39;t forget that towards the end of the page are links for some great pointers to persuade your boss to send you!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>User Defenders Live Podcast at An Event Apart Denver</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/user-defenders-live-at-an-event-apart-denver/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-04T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/user-defenders-live-at-an-event-apart-denver/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/i9mTeKl3NVQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/toddlibby/&quot;&gt;If you follow me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; then you know I was at An Event Apart in October out in Denver, Colorado. I was asked to video this panel of wonderful people for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://userdefenders.com/&quot;&gt;User Defenders&lt;/a&gt; Live Podcast by Jason Ogle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I happily accepted and shot this all on my iPhone 11 Max Pro. I&#39;m glad the video came out as well as it did and I am glad I was there to see this podcast live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When hiring and seeking out talent that is diverse for your teams, try keeping that diverse talent and retaining those people. Why do so many folks leave design and business when they have brought in a wealth of knowledge and expertise?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear the panel that consists of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MinaMarkham/&quot;&gt;Mina Markham&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/farai_uxguy/&quot;&gt;Farai Madzima&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/feather/&quot;&gt;Derek Featherstone&lt;/a&gt; as they answer questions and provide thoughtful and useful answers to questions like how do we keep diverse talent and other topics covered in just under an hour at An Event Apart Denver. Moderated by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jasonogle/&quot;&gt;Jason Ogle&lt;/a&gt;, who runs a terrific podcast and I suggest people in UX subscribe, become a patron, and support &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/UserDefenders/&quot;&gt;User Defenders&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire event was great to be able to attend, but this was one of the reasons why I took the trip to Denver and attend An Event Apart. Besides all the speakers and the three days of great content and great people, I wanted to be here live for this event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The panel was made up of three people that know their stuff in the industry and were a pleasure to meet and talk with. They had a alot of great things to say, a lot of great points were made, and the hour was a pleasure to have been able to have been there for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the video, soak it all in, hear what everyone had to say, take the information with you, and make your workplace a better one for everyone! I learned so much just by being in the fornt row and listening intently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well worth the travel, well worth the trip, well worth it all. I cannot express how fun this event was, how great the people were and how terrific the venue was as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Contrasting Accessibility with Color Contrast</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/contrasting-accessibility-with-color-contrast/"/>
		<updated>2019-12-19T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/contrasting-accessibility-with-color-contrast/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Color contrast is something that is important when designing and developing what we are putting on the web. The strides we have taken are many regarding accessibility, but there is still a long way to go and I will show you some examples, as well as why we need to do a better job at making sure color contrast is covered in our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day, during my time online doing some research, I was looking into some conferences to attend in 2020. One website I stumbled upon had some major accessibility issues regarding color contrast. Forms, an embedded, third-party form from an event website where you buy tickets from that was totally ”invisible“. I couldn&#39;t see any of the form. It&#39;s as if it was not there at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/huh.png&quot; alt=&quot;A website for a conference that has a form but all that you can see is a white background and no form at all.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Where is the form to register? In this example, this was a third-party form that was not showing up in Firefox for some reason. The form worked in Chromium-based browsers. This was another aspect of accessibility that was not met. Not everyone uses a Chromium-based browser.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we make it better as a community of designers and developers? We must think about these folks and this is where the need for accessibility in the process comes in. While accessibility encompasses a lot of different aspects of design and development, I am focusing right now solely on color contrast in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Color contrast is defined as;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/contrasting-accessibility-with-color-contrast/Dictionary.com&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;noun&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The change in the appearance of a colour surrounded by another colour; for example, grey looks bluish if surrounded by yellow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the World Health Organization (WHO);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Globally, at least 2.2 billion people have a vision impairment or blindness, of whom at least 1 billion have a vision impairment that could have been prevented or has yet to be addressed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This 1 billion people includes those with moderate or severe distance vision impairment or blindness due to unaddressed refractive error, as well as near vision impairment caused by unaddressed presbyopia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Globally, the leading causes of vision impairment are uncorrected refractive errors and cataracts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The majority of people with vision impairments are over the age of 50 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/contrasting-accessibility-with-color-contrast/Rachel%20R.%20Vasquez&quot;&gt;Contrasting colors, also known as complementary colors, are colors from opposing segments of the color wheel. Colors that are directly across from one another on a basic color wheel provide maximum contrast.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are at least 2.2 billion people who suffer from a vision impairment or some form of color blindness and I&#39;ll share with you some of those types of color blindness and vision impairments below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;types-of-color-blindness&quot;&gt;Types of Color Blindness&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are seven total types of color blindness including monochromacy (the absence of color perception).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;red-green-color-blindness&quot;&gt;Red-green color blindness&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most common type of color blindness makes it difficult to tell the difference between red and green. There are four types of red-green color blindness;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deuteranomaly:&lt;/em&gt; This is the most common type of red-green color blindness. This type is mild and usually does not hinder normal viewing or activities. It makes green look more red.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Protoanomaly:&lt;/em&gt; This makes red look more green and less bright. This is also mild as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Protonopia&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;deutueranopia:&lt;/em&gt; Both of these make it so that you cannot tell the difference between red and green at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;blue-yellow-color-blindness&quot;&gt;Blue-yellow color blindness&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This less-common type of color blindness makes it difficult for people to tell the difference between blue and green, and red and yellow. There are two types of blue-yellow color blindness;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tritananomaly:&lt;/em&gt; Which makes it hard to tell the difference between blue and green, and red and yellow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tritanopia:&lt;/em&gt; Is when you are unable to tell the difference between blue and green, purple and red, and pink and yellow. Colors also look a lot less bright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;complete-color-blindness&quot;&gt;Complete Color Blindness&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Monochromacy:&lt;/em&gt; Is also known as Complete Color Blindness. Where you cannot see colors at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;stargardt&#39;s&quot;&gt;Stargardt&#39;s&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stargardt&#39;s, a type of macular degeneration that means people who have it, lose vision in the center of the retina. It is an inherited disorder of the retina. A disease which causes vision loss during childhood or adolescence, although it may not be noticed until adulthood. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twoblindbrothers.com/pages/reveal&quot;&gt;Here is an example of a site&lt;/a&gt; that allows visitors to see through the eyes of the founders, and what they see when they navigate the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/contrasting-accessibility-with-color-contrast/Designer/Developer&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don&#39;t need to worry about this! Our customers are under 50!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about temporary impairment or injury? Watery eyes by getting punched in the nose by an over-enthusiastic pet or child? (Yes, that was me) An eye injury when you socked yourself in the eye trying to adjust the sun visor in your car while driving? (Yes, that was me again).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use of one eye just for a short period of time? There are times where a temporary impairment comes into play more than likely, just as with other forms of accessibility issues (broken hand, wrist in a cast, eye patch, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe Dad is looking online for a gift for his kids? Maybe the user under 50 has an impairment? You don&#39;t know this, so we can&#39;t assume. We do not know our users. We do not know who the users are (unless you have done extensive user research, which we should be doing) and of whom will be using the sites we build or the apps we create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s no possible way anyone will interview every single user of the product. So assuming we know who the user is, is not something we should be doing. So do not assume that you know all your users or customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We as designers and developers should know at the very least, the basics of this. That there are people out there with certain visual impairments that make it difficult for them to see certain colors and that we need to make our work more adjusted to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, we have certain color palettes we like, but is the end result of our work we do for us as designers and developers? Or is it for the end user? The people that will view the work we do as we move on to other projects and maybe take a look at what we have done once in a great while?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should all be working together to make sure that these levels of accessibility are met in our work. It is 2020 and we are still having this conversation, even more now than ever it seems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why aren&#39;t we at a place where this is part of accessibility testing? All it takes, is some really simple testing for color contrast. You can even do it in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Tools&quot;&gt;Firefox DevTools&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-tools&quot;&gt;The Tools&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Color contrast checkers. There are many. I mean &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt;. There is one I use to make sure what I am doing uses the correct level of color contrasting, it is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://colourcontrast.cc/&quot;&gt;Colour Contrast Checker&lt;/a&gt; or over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://whocanuse.com/&quot;&gt;WhoCanUse&lt;/a&gt;. for a more thorough look if I am having issues with certain colors regarding background and body copy. I know there are a lot of tools and resources, and maybe some that aren&#39;t covered here. These are a few I use or have as a part of my workflow when checking for accessibility with color contrast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does color contrast have to meet those standards? In my opinion? Yes. There is debate around the contrast of white text on backgrounds as opposed to black text on backgrounds of the same color. We should be finding the right color combinations with regards to text color on background color in our work though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tests have shown that people with visual impairments find reading white text on a certain colored background are easier than reading the same text in black font. I ran into this when testing color contrast for a project I am working on regarding white and black text on certain orange and blue backgrounds. Text and interface components have different contrast ratios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you may want to try and achieve 100% WCAG 2.0 AA compliance, you most likely will meet AAA and AA standards for your project due to different ratios of text contrast and component contrast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designers should know about color contrast. Developers should understand color contrast. Again, at the least the very basics or theory of color contrast. We need to understand this to put this knowledge into our workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/ccc.png&quot; alt=&quot;Colorcontrast.cc - A terrific color contrast checking tool for quick testing.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The site colourcontrast.cc with a yellow-ish background with black text. A color contrast tool online that measures the color contrasts between background and foreground colors with hex values for colors, sliders for hue, saturation, and lightness. Also pass/fail indicators regarding WCAG 2.0 AA and AAA.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://whocanuse.com/&quot;&gt;Who Can Use&lt;/a&gt; is another fantastic contrast checker that will become a staple in my accessibility testing most definitely. It gives you a look at the different contrasts and how they stack up versus the many different kinds of visual impairments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://contrast-ratio.com/&quot;&gt;Lea Verou has an excellent color contrast checker&lt;/a&gt; she made that is a great tool for checking color contrast as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/wcu.png&quot; alt=&quot;Who Can Use - A phenomenal color contrast checking tool.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The site Who Can Use which gives color combinations, their contrast numbers, simulation of text, and the different impairments and their percentages in population, WCAG grading and that is more in depth that most tools for testing against the different types of visual impairments.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://contrastchecker.com/&quot;&gt;The WCAG Contrast Checker&lt;/a&gt; is another option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/wcagcc.png&quot; alt=&quot;The WCAG Contrast Checker.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The WCAG Contrast Checker. Which shows foreground and background color selection, sample text and ratio information along with pass/fail markers, a button to switch on/off for grayscale view, and much more.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://webaim.org/resources/contrastchecker/&quot;&gt;WebAIM Contrast Checker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/webaimcc.png&quot; alt=&quot;The WebAIM Contrast Checker. &quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The WebAIM Contrast Checker which shows foreground and background color selection, sample text and ratio information.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wave.webaim.org/extension/&quot;&gt;The WAVE Web Extension&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/axe-web-accessibility-tes/lhdoppojpmngadmnindnejefpokejbdd&quot;&gt;Axe Web Accessibility Extension&lt;/a&gt; are a couple of browser extensions/add-on&#39;s I use among other color contrast checking sites and tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wave.webaim.org/&quot;&gt;WAVE&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deque.com/tools/&quot;&gt;Deque&lt;/a&gt; have great accessibility testing tools that not only check for color contrast issues, but all accessibility issues as well. Chrome and Firefox have add-on&#39;s for their respective browsers when it comes to color contrast checkers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Color contrast checking is super important. Why? Do we really want to have instances in forms where we cannot read the form labels? With flat design being popular still, do we really want to be searching for a text field to input our information into a form we&#39;re trying to send to the people that run the website?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to be able to clearly see a form field so I can enter information into it. So imagine someone with an impairment visually, trying to do this. Text colors and form components have two different kinds of contrast ratios. They are not the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting the information to the user is crucial. If you&#39;re not getting that information to the user in an effective manner, then that&#39;s not good UX and it certainly is not good accessibility if people can&#39;t understand the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you even tried to read your phone with the glare of the sun on the screen? Probably, and you can&#39;t really read what you&#39;re trying to look at. You have to adjust so that the sun isn&#39;t hitting the screen on the phone in a way that you can read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to get the information off the device so you can understand what you&#39;re looking at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a minute and squint at whatever you&#39;re looking at. Can you read it clearly? Probably not. So remember those who have visual deficiencies and get them the information they are looking for in a clear manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some colors look good to some people (designers, I&#39;m looking at you) but will they look good to people that have deuteranomaly? What about people with tritanopia? How is that information getting to them with your color scheme?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;wcag-aa-%26-aaa-definitions&quot;&gt;WCAG AA &amp;amp; AAA Definitions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/contrasting-accessibility-with-color-contrast/Internet%20Person&quot;&gt;So what is an acceptable level of color contrast?&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A minimum color contrast ratio recommended by ISO-9241-3 and ANSI-HFES-100-1988 is 3:1 for standard text and vision. The 4.5:1 ratio takes into account color deficiencies, low visual acuities, or loss of contrast sensitivity. 4.5:1 is also the chosen level for WCAG AA standards because “&lt;em&gt;it compensated for the loss in contrast sensitivity usually experienced by users with visiion loss equivalent to approximately 20/40 vision&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The minimum level for WCAG AAA is 7:1 and the reason for that is;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/contrasting-accessibility-with-color-contrast/WCAG&quot;&gt;&amp;hellip;because it compensated for the loss in contrast sensitivity usually experienced by users with vision loss equivalent to approximately 20/80 vision. People with more than this degree of vision loss usually use assistive technologies to access their content (and the assistive technologies usually have contrast enhancing, as well as magnification capability built into them).&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These calculations are made for the size of body text and a relaxed contrast ratio is provided for larger text, such as headings or any other text which is larger than the body copy. Remember to make link text stand out and underlined as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While these are the minimum and suggested ratios for each level (AA &amp;amp; AAA), interface components do not have the same contrast ratios. While text is 4.5:1 in WCAG AA, interface components are 3:1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text requires a higher contrast because people are trying to read it. Interface components do not and therefore have a lower standard. You can still do your best to get as close as you can to WCAG guidelines when it comes to using an accessibility checker like WAVE, WebAIM, or the Deque Accessibility Checker but having some things AAA compliant and some AA is quite alright, just as long as everything passes you&#39;re being an a11y!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;forms&quot;&gt;Forms&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picture yourself on a website looking for some conference tickets, you&#39;re shopping around for information and doing some research on conferences. You&#39;re looking for a newsletter to sign up with to keep in the loop or to learn something. Now you run into something like this;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/si1.png&quot; alt=&quot;A blue form on a website, with darker blue form fields that aren&#39;t very discernable, with black text in the form fields with a hot pink submit button.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;A case of bad color contrast in a subscription form.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a challenge for me when I came across it, so imagine what it must be like for someone with a visual impairment. While someone with a visual impairment can differentiate between colors, the contrast fo this form and many others I have seen aren&#39;t that good. This is where color contrast comes into the conversation. A conversation we &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; need to have. Still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then why are we running into instances of this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/ewww.png&quot; alt=&quot;A form submission message in white font on a neon yellow background which makes reading nearly impossible and color contrast almost non-existant.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Wait, what?! An even worse case of color contrast on a confirmation dialog after form submission.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is someone with good vision supposed to read that? How is someone with a vision impairment supposed to read that if they do not use a screen reader? This kind of color contrast is not helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is unreadable even to someone like myself who has good eyesight, so what about someone that doesn&#39;t have good eyesight, someone that is older? It has to be next to impossible to get the information from this confirmation message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the hardest time reading this and making out the sentence, &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Thanks for subscribing! Please check your email for further instructions.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; Why is this happening in this day and age? It got me thinking, my vision (for now) is just fine, but what about people that have visual impairments? How could, and how &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; they read that?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I have submitted a form, I would like to be able to read any confirmation messages after the submission. I don&#39;t know about other folks, but I just like to read the information relayed to me after submission in case there is anything I shouldn&#39;t miss or some tidbit of information that I need to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Please check your inbox to confirm your subscription.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“Your confirmation number will be sent to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:user@address.com&quot;&gt;user@address.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/em&gt; or,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“Your ticket number is 98765. Check your inbox to confirm receipt.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if your form uses a color contrast that isn&#39;t as sharp as it needs to be, there could be a lot of people not getting the information you&#39;re trying to get to them or unable to get information from your user(s) because they cannot read the information displayed. A confirmation message needs to be relayed clearly so as to get the user the information the user should know upon submission as I mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-can-we-do%3F&quot;&gt;What Can We Do?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We as designers and developers need to do better, to have a system of checks and balances to make sure that color contrast is an integral part of the design process. We have learned through many mistakes we have seen over the last few years that accessibility reaches a far wider scope that sometimes is ignored by the masses, myself included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;How can we make sure we are paying attention to color contrast when we design and develop websites?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; you may ask? Well…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Test with persons with vision impairments.&lt;/strong&gt; If we can ask on Twitter for users of a specific demographic, then we can ask for persons to test with vision impairments. Even going as far as hiring those people to work on your teams to make the process better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make accessibility inclusive in the design and development process.&lt;/strong&gt; If we are including time to make sure what we are doing right from the start is accessible, then we are halfway there. And be even more inclusive… Hire persons with visual impairments to your team to help with the process with their expertise on the matter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&#39;t follow the WCAG guidelines focusing solely on color contrast for text.&lt;/strong&gt; Different components of a site or application have different color contrasts. Forms, buttons, text, interface components. Use good judgment and you will be able to differentiate between them all and use a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.color-blindness.com/coblis-color-blindness-simulator/&quot;&gt;color-blindness simulator&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.colororacle.org/&quot;&gt;there are some&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webexhibits.org/causesofcolor/index.html&quot;&gt;to choose&lt;/a&gt; from that are good. There is even an extension for Chrome called &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/colorblindly/floniaahmccleoclneebhhmnjgdfijgg&quot;&gt;Colorblindly&lt;/a&gt; and one called &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/colorblinding/dgbgleaofjainknadoffbjkclicbbgaa&quot;&gt;Colorblinding&lt;/a&gt; as well. Make sure &lt;em&gt;everything passes&lt;/em&gt; and accessibility check!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be sensible with colors.&lt;/strong&gt; Ask yourself, “Would this color scheme work for others with vision impairments?” Use color schemes and palettes that work and that make sense. Pastels are okay, but not in a Miami Vice nightmare landscape kind of horrible way. And… Color-blind people can tell the difference between colors, they just have  hard time distinguishing between those colors. And…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use the tools!&lt;/strong&gt; Color contrast checkers like in the examples I have provided and accessibility tools that are plentiful out there, use them! That&#39;s why they are there! They will inform you of issues before you push to production or go live, saving you (and/or your company) time and money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the WCAG guidelines is something we should do, accessible and inclusive design is something we &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; do. Make sure everything passes an accessibility check through one of these tools you have made a part of your workflow. Adjust colors and contrasts where you can and where you need to in order to fulfill the requirements for AA and AAA compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of talk about accessibility and we have taken tremendous strides to making the web more accessible and inclusive but we have a long way to go still from it being all-inclusive. So let&#39;s make the web more inclusive, but also remember how and why. Also reminding ourselves to actually do it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a broad spectrum of vision deficiencies and impairments we need to address during the design phase of the process. Making this process more inclusive by taking the time to make sure color contrast (and other aspects of accessibility) work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us remind ourselves of the fact not everyone has perfect or near perfect vision. Embrace the process of color contrast, avoid illegible parts of websites that are created and unintelligible forms like in the examples I provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zeldman&quot;&gt;Jeffrey Zeldman&lt;/a&gt; summarized it up in his post on Blue Beanie Day (November 30th) when he wrote;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/contrasting-accessibility-with-color-contrast/Jeffrey%20Zeldman&quot;&gt;&amp;hellip;our industry as a whole thinks less and less about accessibility (not that we ever had an A game on the subject), and talks less and less about progressive enhancement, preferring to chase the ephemeral goal posts of over-engineered solutions to non-problems.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;closing&quot;&gt;Closing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We as architects and craftspersons of the web community must keep everyone in mind when it comes to not only color contrast with fonts, websites, User Experience, forms, and colors, but all areas of accessibility and inclusive design as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we should follow WCAG rules explicitly, we have to remember again that certain components of a website or an application have two different types of contrast to them. Toggles, components, text, buttons, form labels. Keep in mind the contrast ratios between each and we can make things that are great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear color contrast is just the beginning, but it&#39;s one of the great ways to start building, creating, and handcrafting great, accessible sites for all.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>User Defenders Book Club</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/user-defenders-book-club/"/>
		<updated>2020-02-01T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/user-defenders-book-club/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was a pleasure being a part of this discussion about a book I really liked. Mike Monteiro&#39;s &lt;em&gt;Ruined By Design&lt;/em&gt;. Have a look at the video below and join User Defenders for more community events and more book club discussions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OfxEJvJ5GsQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This took place in November of 2019, I was just getting around to posting this after the holidays, new year, busy times and lots of stuff going on in life. My book club companions for the discussion are Jason Ogle and Ross Beitzel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I joined in a bit late, I had just gotten back into the office after my afternoon workout , which explains my disheveled look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my first ever foray into being online in this capacity, so please forgive the looking up at absolutely nothing, I have the worst habit in the world of doing that when I am trying to find things to say and thinking of words to use. Enjoy the video and become a patron today!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Deceptive Patterns In Programs We Trust</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/deceptive-patterns-in-programs-we-trust/"/>
		<updated>2020-02-23T19:00:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/deceptive-patterns-in-programs-we-trust/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t look now but you&#39;re probably installing something else other than what you downloaded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was doing computer work for people (installing, networking, tutoring, etc.) I would install software for people that they could afford. Whether it was open source, or whether it was paid software. Usually, open source or freeware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then in the past decade I noticed a huge increase in a deceptive pattern which at the time I thought was just something to click by and not give too much thought to. The “Download Google Chrome” epidemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I said epidemic because it is everywhere it seems. Software companies are in bed with Google (or Alphabet, if you prefer) and they are cashing in, in ways you couldn’t even imagine. Your data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I started to get calls about how &lt;em&gt;“Chrome is on my computer and I don’t know what it is.”&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;“I need you to come fix this for me. It’s telling me to update the program.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These people (mainly older folks) do not know what to do with software the majority of the time I have found. Or they just don’t care. They want to click through and get things done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this company putting this deceptive pattern in their software? I decided to do a bit of research into why. I couldn’t find &lt;strong&gt;anything&lt;/strong&gt; about the topic, but I figured there was only one reason why. Money. The thing that makes big tech run rampant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a few searches for these deceptive patterns and how they are being addressed and I could find absolutely nothing. No mention of these little shady checkboxes and these little tucked away “Here, we suggest you to download Chrome!” content areas. Nothing at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found several instances of &lt;em&gt;“Reasons Why Google Chrome Is Bad”&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;“Top 10 Reasons Not To Download Chrome”&lt;/em&gt; I already know these reasons because I am a little tech savvy. My customers are not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an 80-year-old man that keeps up with family on Facebook and checks e-mail online and that’s it and he’s had programs he and his wife needs and they all had the Download Google Chrome fever. This man does not need Chrome, hasn’t heard of Chrome, and will never use Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;applications&quot;&gt;Applications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take for instance Piriform, the makers of CCleaner. An app that cleans out extraneous crap out of your hard drive and does a number of other things to help the performance fo your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mac and Windows have versions and both have their little differences (Windows versions cleans your registry for instance). When installing the program, you reach a screen that looks something similar to this;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/ccleaner.png&quot; alt=&quot;CCleaner by Piriform installation screen.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The CCleaner installer asks you to install the program. Fine. That’s what you want to do. But if you look in the lower left hand corner, you can see where _&amp;ldquo;Piriform recommends Google Chrome&amp;rdquo;_. Why?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does someone need to download a “recommendation” when they may be completely satisfied with the browser they have already? Or, in the case of many of my customers, they don’t even know what a browser is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, they skip over it because they either click through wanting to install the product and do not want to see all these modal windows and dialogue boxes, or they just do not see the small little checkbox in the lower left-hand corner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some folks do not! Your &lt;strong&gt;“recommendation”&lt;/strong&gt; may not be wanted, needed, or even cared about. I know none of my customers wants Google Chrome and if they already have it, they don’t need this extra, unnecessary step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worst part about this is, that it is probably one of the worst pieces of surveillance software there is out there that is available to consumers. Here is yet another example of this deceptive pattern in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/avgfree.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;AVG Anti-Virus program installation screen.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;As you can see, the checkbox is checked. They are 100% of the time when I deal with software that uses this deceptive pattern through deception.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Is Chrome going to give you faster access to your favorite sites? Will your searches be easier with Google built into the address bar? Is the browser really stable and secure? Do my customers really care about ANY of that? I’ve asked many of my customers, and they have all said the same thing. No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;100% of my customers, that’s 27 customers whom I do computer work for and teach them how to use things all have said the same thing. &lt;em&gt;“I don’t care what I use for a browser I just want to check Facebook, look at my grandkids photos and check my e-mail.”&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is all my customers who are older want to do. Nothing else. They’re not doing development, graphic design or anything other than playing games, Facebook, e-mail, and _maybe_video chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With people being very trusting, one could say even naive, they expect the products they use, the products I am installing, to be free of anything intrusive so they don’t have to call me wondering what Google Chrome is or wondering why they have Google Chrome on their computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;emails&quot;&gt;Emails&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another instance of deceptive patterns in UX brought me to the NBA and email. I voted for the All-Star Game and thought, _“well… that’s that. Back to work.”_and lo and behold that was not that. That was only the beginning of the onslaught of emails from the NBA and &lt;a href=&quot;http://nba.com/&quot;&gt;NBA.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://toddl.dev/img/nbaemail.png&quot; alt=&quot;An email from NBA.com.&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;No unsubscribe link on the bottom of the email where they usually are, tucked way down on the bottom, in 10-11 pixel font, clustered in a deep paragraph of legal mumble-ese.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where is the unsubscribe link? I voted for players for the All-Star Game and when I finished I got bombarded with emails so I had to refer to another email that I had been inundated with to find an unsubscribe link to actually unsubscribe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even then, it was going to take 24-48 hours for that to happen! Some I have even seen take fourteen (yes, 14!) business days to unsubscribe! What?! Two business weeks to unsubscribe?! Are you kidding me?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;deceptive-patterns&quot;&gt;Deceptive Patterns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doug Collins, in one of his great videos on UX deceptive patterns below, talks about some of the ways deceptive patterns work. The examples I used use reading patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wo3OPM6jmOM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “Google Chrome Download” uses trust and perceived value. Trust that you need to download Chrome. The perceived value that Chrome is the right browser for you to use. It’s almost as if Piriform is saying, “Piriform uses Google Chrome and since you use our software, you should use what we use!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiding this little checkbox and blurb in the bottom left corner of a dialog box is a deceptive pattern Don’t let anyone fool you. More than likely (and in about 9 out of 10 cases I have seen first hand) people are going to click through and not pay any attention to that step. They want to download the software and use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a pattern that I even skip when I am installing programs. I consider myself a bit savvy when it comes to tech, so those times where I am clicking through because I want to install the program, this step can be skipped very easily. So what do we do about it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-what-can-we-do-about-this%3F&quot;&gt;So What Can We Do About This?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I reached out to Piriform on Twitter. I tweeted that it is a bad thing for them to do since I install their product on my customers computers and they don’t need the extra garbage that their product cleans out in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They did respond (which I did not expect) with they were working on bettering their product (which remains to be seen) and they were listening to their customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, if they are listening to their customers, they will take the screen and that option to download Chrome off their products (they also have a paid version of CCleaner (CCleaner Pro).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to be vigilant. I have to be more vigilant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the latest in the saga that is Avast and their problems with data, I am not going to be installing their products (Avast or AVG Anti Virus) on computers any longer (Windows Defender and Malwarebytes are enough protection in my opinion).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calling out these companies, calling out these deceptive patterns and making sure they are not being used to mislead or misdirect people, especially older folks like my customers is the key to at least slowing down this practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until consumers start pressuring these companies to stop this practice, it will keep going on until they start losing money. Let’s start getting on these companies and get them to stop these deceptive patterns in programs we trust.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Coronavirus, Quarantine, and Chats</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/coronavirus-quarantine-and-chats/"/>
		<updated>2020-03-21T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/coronavirus-quarantine-and-chats/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the past couple of weeks I have been holding some Zoom chats for whomever wanted to come in and just talk to someone. It didn’t have to be on anything gin particular and could be about whatever the person wanted to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a few calls with some great people from around the world and it reminded me of the dial-up days when I &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; thought it was fascinating that I was talking to someone in a chat room from half a world today. That feeling I got when I had amazement at the wonders of technology. I relived that each time I talk to someone in far off places like Nepal, Saudi Arabia, India, Israel, and even the west coast of the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I have been out a few times in order to seek essentials, I have played it safe and stayed indoors for the most part keeping that social distancing practice going. Will I admit to perfect adherence? No. I can’t. Matter of fact I went to the gym a couple times and I was one of maybe four people there. That practice has ceased as of last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reflecting on how one careless person, if sick, does not wipe down the machinery they are using (it happens a lot from what I have seen and heard) I didn’t want to take that risk, especially when dealing with members of my family (mother, father, and sister).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chats have been great. Talking about programming and hobbies, people asking me all sorts of questions about where I live and who I am, what I do, and even some questions about American life and politics (asking about the current occupant in Washington D.C. which I answer as best I can from my point of view but that’s an opinion of what I see).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only had one instance of a call with someone from Israel where someone came into the chat and tried to be a troll. There is a fine art to being a troll, I should know. I used to be one. The attempt was pathetic and just sad to be honest. They should have probably stuck with their day job to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&#39;t go into specifics, but it was a horrible troll job. It was an even worse job if saying what the female said to me in the chat was trying to hurt me or my feelings in some way because it didn&#39;t work at all. That kind of childish thing only solicited an eye roll and a quick scoff and soon I was focus on one of many things I have preoccupying my time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll keep holding these chats but I am going to think of muring up the experience a little bit and I am used to this kind of thing happening. Back in the days of dial-up and chat rooms it happened with more frequency and the trolls back then were far more superior than the feeble attempt by the one I ran into last night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been invited to a lot of places and learned a lot of things with these chats. I hope that through this crisis worldwide (now state-side here in the US) more people jump in and just talk about things like programming and hobbies, things people would talk about face-to-face in a café or diner. Just everyday things, anything that was on their minds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is one thing positive about this whole ordeal many of us are going through with this pandemic it’s that all people want to do is reach out, have a chat with another human being, and learn. Those things I have been doing and the learning has been the best part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning about other people’s cultures and where they live.Learning about their work. I hope it has brought them a little bit of positive in an otherwise gloomy world we have been dealing with since the pandemic broke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re all in this together. Nature has shown us that it is sick and tired of dealing with our egocentric minds. Let’s be kinder to the Earth and definitely let’s reach out and be kinder to our fellow human beings as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Ruminations &amp; Revelations</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/ruminations-and-revelations/"/>
		<updated>2020-04-04T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/ruminations-and-revelations/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ruminations-%26-revelations&quot;&gt;Ruminations &amp;amp; Revelations&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately it occurs to me what a long, strange trip it&#39;s been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— The Grateful Dead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;2%3A33-am-on-a-cold%2C-dark-morning&quot;&gt;2:33 am On A Cold, Dark Morning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I awoke after nodding off to sleep early, as I usually do now that I approaching fifty years of age, with a feeling of despair. With that hollow feeling of emptiness and loneliness that is a part of living alone. I had just decided to take a break from tech. I usually do when I feel like I have been pushed to the brink of going batty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about back when I was a kid. When I found computing, programming, it was an amazing time to be alive. Simple, privileged, tucked away from the madness that had gone on around me (unknowingly) for decades. The things you only heard and read in school texts as a kid growing up about the South and the horrible things that went on there during the Civil Rights marches and era of the Sixties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These thoughts criss-crossed my mind in a woven pattern, such is my brain, of wires that were just an utter mess. When I found programming and computing it had been able to take me away from the blight of being a skinny, tall, and awkward white kid from the ‘burbs of Portland, Maine, who had been yanked out of his home in the city and brought not too far away, yet far away enough that it felt like an eternity and exiled to a rural area in northern New Hampshire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programming took my mind off of things that I had resented my father about and how I held onto those resentments for nearly thirty-five years. My parents had purchased a Commodore 64. Whether it was for the entire family, or just for myself, I do not recall, but I took that computer and hijacked it from the living room to my bedroom and it never saw another room for the entirety of the times we owned it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read the manual cover to cover in a day. I poured through books that I had purchased at book stores. I wanted to learn and program because it was an escape from an otherwise not-so-great, but privileged childhood. Little did I know the teen years would be a huge test and a test that I would fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-dawn-of-my-internet&quot;&gt;The Dawn of My Internet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I discovered the internet back in its infancy when it became public I was gobsmacked to say the least. I remember we got an America Online subscription with a 286 desktop computer we purchased. I still had the C64 and still programmed in BASIC on it. Creating “Choose Your Own Adventure” games I had copied right from the book series. Text versions of books I had found turning those into “Choose Your Own Adventure” games as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when that desktop was plugged into that phone line and that 2400 baud modem kicked on and that dial tone began, converting over to that screech and pinging we who lived that era all know very well, was the beginning of something that some thirty-six years later, I would have never thought I would be involved in and had a passion for deeply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversing with some people in other countries blew my mind. I also was playing RPG’s online as well. The first incantation of Neverwinter Nights was something I started to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it all started with a big blue book, and one week of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;html.-how-todd-mastered-the-language&quot;&gt;HTML. How Todd Mastered the Language&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read that SAMS book “Teach Yourself Web Publishing with HTML and XHTML in 21 Days” in one week. I used Notepad as my code editor after reading about how it could be used to do so and I hit the ground running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took my mind off the things I was struggling with. School. Very few friends. Isolation. Having moved away from where I called “home”. It took my mind and made me think, made me want to create and made me want to learn. I poured through that book and did everything to the letter in that book and understood it all. School did not captivate my mind like this. Math didn’t. History didn’t. Nothing did. Except this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;web-standards%3F-what-is-this%3F&quot;&gt;Web Standards? What Is This?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t quite remember how, or why, but I do remember it was in the Waldenbooks store in the local mall in the small little town I had lived near that was as close to the city as I would get for a number of years of growing up and I found this orange book with a picture of a bearded fellow that seemed to be blurred or pixelated. Bright colors always grabbed my attention, this book did just that. I purchased the book and proceeded to go home and read a little bit of it. That little bit turned into a day of reading the entire first edition of “Designing with Web Standards” by Jeffrey Zeldman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest is history. A history fraught with highs and lows, ups and downs, the good, the bad, and the downright ugly. Such is life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through thirty years of addictions, alcoholism, drugs, and horrible decisions I had strayed away from the thing that I found as a young kid and moved to do with the passion that I had only had in one other thing and that was playing basketball. When I chose the party scene after my sophomore year of high school, my dream of being the small forward for the Boston Celtics disintegrated before my very eyes as ego and addiction took over my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though I always kept that orange book. I sometimes would open up that orange book in times of being low, having nothing to do. Reading about the man who wrote the book, visiting and reading his site in the early days like that was my main news source. Never knowing that someday, as an adult, I would finally meet that man and get to thank him and even call him friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-times%2C-they-are-%E2%80%98a-changin%E2%80%99&quot;&gt;The Times, They Are ‘A Changin’&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to now. I’m forty-nine years old. I have seen the browser wars, I have seen the advent of pop up’s, pop overs, pop unders, advertisements clogging up our web landscape, the monetization of the web. The dark underbelly of the web in its infancy. All the way to the dark web of now and only a small fraction of that dark web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We turned something so simple, into something so complex and perverted like human beings always do with anything we come in contact with. Such is the way with the web and such is the way with programming languages. Simple is never enough. We always look to and stumble into a way to convolute and fuck up everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also seen the glimpses of good, the glimmers of hope. The advent of CSS, Eric Meyer’s “Eric Meyer on CSS”, The Mosaic and Netscape browsers, chat rooms and mIRC. ICQ and BBSs. Gopher and Telnet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brilliant minds that made the infrastructure of the web as we know it today. Woz, Berners-Lee, Wium Lie, even Jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those whose exploits served as reminders nothing is safe and security is key like Mitnick, Poulson, Lamo, and Blankenship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The passion and the curiosity faded. I was empty and a shell of my former self, I was hollow and devoid of any feeling and I just did not want to live. I had struggled with depression since an early age, probably nine years old. Having been bullied shortly before moving from Maine to New Hampshire, it only got worse. Some of my family was target for a group of bullies in the area in which we lived in. My maternal grandfather included for the longest time before his death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sank into depression and more drinking and spiraled out of control. Drugs soon entered again. I did not care anymore about a lot of things. I thought I did not care about anything. I did. I just wasn’t aware of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I awoke in the mornings or in most cases, came to in the morning and didn’t want to live. I wished I hadn’t woken up. I wish that I did not have to go to the same shitty jobs i had outside of the web that I had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this day, I still awake sometimes, and wish that I hadn’t. When I look at Twitter, when I used to read news. When I used to try and converse with people I followed on Twitter and got back not a single reply. I just wish I hadn’t woken up that morning. I took it all too personal. Yet, I took it all and just did not care and beat myself into the ground with the thousand ways why this was all so horribly bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sobriety%2C-perseverance%2C-and-fight&quot;&gt;Sobriety, Perseverance, and Fight&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013 I decided it would be a good idea to get sober. A decision I do not regret to this day. It did not however go as smoothly as I wanted it to. Then again, does anything major we live through go as smoothly as we wish it to be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first web conference was in Boston in 2008 at An Event Apart. My first meeting with Jeffrey Zeldman was of me having a nervous breakdown because of a credit card mixup. Right in front of the man who wrote the book that I had poured over a hundred times over. I was unfazed at the time because alcohol took that away, but now when I look back I look back with a little sense of embarrassment and shame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not get back until 2017. I don’t remember much about the 2008 AEA except for what I had written down on an old blog and moved the archive over to this incantation. Of all the things I remember it was my first meeting with Jeffrey, Eric, and Bruce Lawson in that dining room at the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to 2013. I worked on a lot of things but a lot of things were in my life that should never have been and never would be again. The wreckage of all that has been cleared and I have lived with much peace and serenity of late. Then Twitter came back into the picture. I also found web design again as a passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had always tried to brand myself and get my name out there so I could land a great job with a great design studio or firm doing what I loved to do. Between 2008 and 2013 I was unable to do any of that because of life events. From 2013-2017 I was able to do a little bit of it. In the meantime from 1999 to this point in, roughly 2017, I was able to keep my head barely above water doing things with computers whether it was hardware repair or web design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few more conferences the past couple of years and getting the nerve to walk up to the people whom I admired and their work helped shape who I was as a web designer, and meeting a ton of great people and having a lot of great conversations along the way, it started to deteriorate within myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;2017.-why%3F&quot;&gt;2017. Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone entered the White House and as fast as the landscape in this country has decayed past any corrupt government I had ever read about or heard of, so did my mental health. Especially on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been removed from Facebook for quite some time, Twitter I figured would remain rock solid and it would be a great place to pitch myself and maybe someday get those bucket list items out of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute to the CSS Working Group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speak at a conference or conferences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write published articles for online publications (A List Apart being one)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help people learn in the web community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and give back to what had been so freely given to me. Knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the landscape of Twitter eroded quickly. Then the factions of certain developers and their giant egos started to lash out at people. Things got ugly and all I saw (and continued to see) was human beings at their ugliest. I started to shut down like I always do and retract back into myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With each passing conference though, I got the courage to put on that face, to engage with the speakers, and mingle. I remember the first time I met Rachel Andrew, I sat down as she worked form the table, and I had adored her work from afar for many years, her and husband Drew McLellan were folks I had learned from, and all I could do is nervously eat my breakfast and talk very little because I was absolutely wrought with anxiety and fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I persisted even if I looked like a complete idiot. The first time I met Jen Simmons I probably babbled on and on. I remember meeting Dm Mall and completely asked a question not even remotely relevant to the talk he gave. It was those kinds of moments that you want to take back but never can, but regardless, I met those people even if I seemed like a giant bumbling fool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-don%E2%80%99t-people-like-me%3F&quot;&gt;Why Don’t People Like Me?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always been a people pleaser. I have always wanted people to like me. That will never be the case because not everyone will like me and not everyone does, this I do know. A friend once told me, “It doesn’t matter what people think of you, it’s none of your business.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That made me think a long time, until I finally realized what it meant. They will think whatever they want about you, let them. You can’t get inside their head and what they do, think, say, it is none of your business. Sometime ignorance can be bliss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, that person unfriended me on Twitter, what did I do or say? This always crossed my mind when that happened. Full of self-doubt and guilt about “what was it I said?” I am a likable person! Hours spent wondering why? Lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People come and people go fro our lives and until I fully realized this, I fully realized that’s going to happen on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-present&quot;&gt;The Present&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all the negative on Twitter. With all the failed job applications and rejection emails that are in the hundreds, approaching the thousands.With the current landscape of being self-quarantined, social media being cesspits for the degenerative society we live in today. The lies, the misinformation, the scandals, and the horrible truths and new low that happen every day it has just become too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a job I had that was just in the final stages of breaking me and my spirit. A broken system, with an even more broken process, with a leadership that has blinders on, pushing back when suggestions for modernization are put on the table, I just couldn’t take it any longer. It was soul crushing and morale destroying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to take a break. This was written up because I couldn’t sleep. Now that I am at the point where I might be able to get another couple hours in I’ll wrap this up. When I commit this to the server and it goes live I’ll still be in my little self-isolation bubble. Not ready to come out yet. I just want to decompress and listen to music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could have written a lot more. Hell I could write a book about my life but I’m sure nobody gives a shit and that’s fine with me because no matter what people think of me it’s none of my business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still had that ember inside of me that hadn’t been extinguished int he 2000’s after being told by several people that I would never make it in web, I would never have a career in web, and I would never amount to anything. Well I may be a nobody on the web, but that’s okay with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still have that orange book, I still have that thirst to learn and create, but right now, imposter syndrome, depression, and anxiety about the future, and having been thinking for a very long time about my own mortality, I just needed to stop tech for awhile and just live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s just been a very emotionally, mentally, and physically draining few months. I wouldn’t wish this loneliness on anyone and when I was talking with someone I referred to the fact that I could almost 100% relate to what must have been running through the mind of Robin Williams. Always wanting to make people laugh and to bring a smile to the faces he entertained. It’s been that bleak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may never get to do what I want to do in web, I may never get that job I always wanted, but for as long as I am left on this earth though, I’ll always have that orange book.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>RWD Turns Ten</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/rwd-turns-10/"/>
		<updated>2020-05-24T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/rwd-turns-10/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are some things I always will remember like it was yesterday that I have learned or read that have helped me along in my web career. Whether it was remembering my od friend the Mosaic browser, when I switched to using Macromedia Fireworks as my vector image tool, the times when I bought such career-altering books such as Laura Lemay&#39;s &lt;em&gt;SAMS Tech Yourself Web Publishing with HTML and XHTML in 21 Days&lt;/em&gt; or Jeffrey Zeldmans &lt;em&gt;Designing With Web Standards&lt;/em&gt; or Eric Meyer&#39;s &lt;em&gt;CSS: The Definitive Guide&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some of the things that will stick with me until I leave this earth, and in the meantime, I have something that is added to that list.Something that I think has changed the landscape of the entire web industry and for every developer and designer alike. That is when Ethan Marcotte coined the term, &lt;em&gt;«Responsive Web Design»&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Ethan Marcotte.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://responsivedesign.is/&quot;&gt;Responsive Web Design is&lt;/a&gt; « ...the combination of flexible grids, flexible images, and media queries. We help take the complexity out of responsive design with details on Design, Development and Strategy. (Taken directly from the website) » and you can learn more about it there and many more places such as at &lt;a href=&quot;https://alistapart.com/article/responsive-web-design/&quot;&gt;A List Apart&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Learn/CSS/CSS_layout/Responsive_Design&quot;&gt;MDN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There used to be a podcast about Responsive Web Design named (yes, you guessed it!) The Responsive Web Design Podcast, which I miss terribly. Why? Guests were great in sharing what they were working on and talking about responsive web design. Plus, Ethan Marcotte and Karen McGrane are two people in the industry I admire, respect (among many), and follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://abookapart.com/products/responsive-web-design&quot;&gt;There is even a book&lt;/a&gt;, if you did not know this. It should be a part of your library. Really. It should.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning Responsive Web Design has been one of the best things that I have had the undertaking of doing. I picked apart that example from A List Apart like a surgeon finely does surgery. When others moved to RWD, I picked apart their layouts as well in order to learn it. The I was able to implement it which in turn I was able to craft websites for my clients using RWD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ethan wrote in the ALA article;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/rwd-turns-10/Ethan%20Marcotte&quot;&gt;Our work is defined by its transience, often refined or replaced within a year or two. Inconsistent window widths, screen resolutions, user preferences, and our users’ installed fonts are but a few of the intangibles we negotiate when we publish our work, and over the years, we’ve become incredibly adept at doing so.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve come into the age of CSS Grid Layout and Flex Layout, and soon(?) Masonry Layout. The future certainly does change rapidly in tech, and we have to be adept to embrace and implement those changes when they come. Ethan only started the journey for me to be this adept when he coined that term in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only is it wonderful to know follow your phenomenal work and monumental contributions to the web over the years, it is a pleasure and I am grateful to know you and to have been able to be a part of this wonderful thing we call web design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy 10th birthday, Responsive Web Design.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>War and Peace, My Version</title>
		<link href="https://toddl.dev/posts/war-and-peace-my-version/"/>
		<updated>2020-08-24T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>https://toddl.dev/posts/war-and-peace-my-version/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/war-and-peace-my-version/Winston%20Churchill&quot;&gt;If you are going through hell, keep going.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually I see that quote attributed to Winston Churchill, of whom I do not particularly care for, but the quote is something I have long subscribed to since I could remember first seeing the quote some time in middle school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I know there are others who have had a rougher time. I know there are those who have had more hurdles and barriers than I. I also know I am a white guy in tech and that comes with privilege. Privilege that I know I have benefitted from in the past in and out of tech. This is not a story about “Oh woe is me”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a story of how the constant beating down has worn me out to the end. There is only so much someone can take. I have seen this with all my friends and peole in tech. Not just me. This is a story though of how it sucks to be in a place where you no longer know what to do or feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/war-and-peace-my-version/Plato&quot;&gt;Only the dead have seen the end of war.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been doing web for a little over twenty-one years now. In that time, I have applied to &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of companies. I didn&#39;t keep a tab until after my first year of designing and developing websites. I think in that first year alone, I probably applied to approximately 5-6 companies. It really wasn&#39;t a thing where I lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then however, the more I poured my heart and soul into making things, creating websites, using Adobe products to make flyers and tri-folds. When I used Quark to make business cards and branded stationery, I knew this was what I wanted to do. I knew that when I was nine-years-old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw a Commodore PET 2001 series running in that classroom I remember so vividly walking by. Then, when we moved from Maine to New Hampshire, I saw them again. Math classroom, one was open, one was running Oregon Trail. I was mesmerised. I wanted to know how they worked and what made them tick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew this was something I &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to do as a career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I learned. And learned. And kept learning up until this very day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I started doing websites back around 1997 for kicks, I decided maybe I could do this thing professionally and started my first “company”. “North Country Web Design”. Even bought a overpriced ad for the Yellow Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/war-and-peace-my-version/H.G.%20Wells&quot;&gt;If you fell down yesterday, stand up today.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I poured everything into that. Then when the burnout came, I took time off, that was my first case of burnout. Then I moved four years later to California. Figured I could do it out there, so I went to school and freelanced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, from 1998 to 2001 I applied to a couple hundred companies. Nothing. So I applied to a few hundred more in 2001. Nothing. 2002-2006 before I moved back to New England, I applied to about 500 companies. Not one job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/war-and-peace-my-version/Maya%20Angelou&quot;&gt;You may encounter many defeats, but you must not be defeated. In fact, it may be necessary to encounter the defeats, so you can know who you are, what you can rise from, how you can still come out of it.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was determined to get a job. So when I moved back to New Hampshire, I applied and applied. And applied… you get the point. When I checked that old Excel spreadsheet last week I had over two thousand companies I had applied to. 2,137 to be exact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many hired me? Two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve always tried to let it roll off my shoulders, but this last time. The last rejection email. It broke me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/war-and-peace-my-version/Edgar%20Allen%20Poe&quot;&gt;I have great faith in fools - self-confidence my friends will call it.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is almost as if I&#39;m Robert Johnson at the crossroads of highways 61 and 49 and I&#39;m willing to sell my soul to the Devil himself if it meant getting a job. Although, it hasn&#39;t quite gotten to that point yet, the thoughts of willing to go to great lengths to get what you want seriously traverses through my brain now and then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&#39;m at the crossroads. Do I quit? Do I remain? Do I sail off into the sunset or do I ride that atom bomb down to the ground like Slim Pickens? Or do I remain the whipping boy to a process that is so broken and fractured?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;content__placeholder&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;content__image&quot; src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/colabottles/image/upload/v1598383747/images/slim_tcpmre.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Slim Pickens in Dr. Strangelove riding the atom bomb out of the plane like a rodeo cowboy&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Slim Pickens in Dr. Strangelove riding the atom bomb out of the plane like a rodeo cowboy.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the one that got to me. Granted, I let my emtions get the better of me sometimes, that is a work in progress, but the fact remains a 0.0009358914% success rate is not what I would call stellar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see it all the time. Folks getting jobs like it was candy being handed out at a candy store. You can learn at the job while on the job, such great succcess stories that I am very happy for all those people, don&#39;t get me wrong. If you have applied to as many places I have you start to wonder when the hell am I going to get a shot?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is what I am facing now. I feel like giving up, to saying, “To hell with all this!” and I have to some people. I am drained and tired of trying to find a home with a company that wil have me because none of them don&#39;t. Maybe that&#39;s a sign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I was saying last night, that a friend of mine once told me, “I&#39;m so happy I didn&#39;t get all the things I ever wanted, because I wouldn&#39;t be where I am today if I had.” And you know what? He is right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this. Just the chance. The chance to learn, to work in a group, to work and succeed. To make great things that benefit and create accessible, inclusive things. You begin to wonder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/war-and-peace-my-version/Sylvia%20Plath&quot;&gt;The worst enemy to creativity is self-doubt.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been doubted my entire life. That I&#39;ll never work in tech, that I&#39;d never be a programmer, that I&#39;d never do some of the things I wanted to do. I proved them all wrong. Friends. Family. Everyone. This time though. This time I&#39;m trying to prove myself wrong and it&#39;s waged a war in my head that is constant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been beaten down too much and been told I am not good enough too many times and I know that is not the case, but the fact remains, those voices still are there, they still speak and when another rejection email comes in the inbox, it is just another case of I am never going to be good enough even with the skills I have and the learning I do daily. Never good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heart tells me to quit. That it can&#39;t take any more rejection. There are issues behind that which I won&#39;t go into. My gut, my gut tells me to keep fighting like I always have and never quit. I have ten to fifteen years left in me and I&#39;m not to stop now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t know or think I have it in me anymore. The constant being beaten down needs to end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something I loved to do since the age of nine, forty years plus ago. I&#39;m ready to leave it all behind but the question is, do I walk away now or hold out hope for yet another day?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://toddl.dev/posts/war-and-peace-my-version/Lemony%20Snicket&quot;&gt;Strange as it may seem, I still hope for the best, even though the best, like an interesting piece of mail, so rarely arrives, and even when it does it can be lost so easily.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
